<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><ContractNotice xmlns="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:ContractNotice-2" xmlns:cac="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonAggregateComponents-2" xmlns:cbc="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonBasicComponents-2" xmlns:efac="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extension-aggregate-components/1" xmlns:efbc="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extension-basic-components/1" xmlns:efext="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extensions/1" xmlns:ext="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonExtensionComponents-2">
  <ext:UBLExtensions>
    <ext:UBLExtension>
      <ext:ExtensionContent>
        <efext:EformsExtension>
          <efbc:TransmissionDate>2025-06-05+00:00</efbc:TransmissionDate>
          <efbc:TransmissionTime>08:49:29+00:00</efbc:TransmissionTime>
          <efac:NoticeSubType>
            <cbc:SubTypeCode listName="notice-subtype">16</cbc:SubTypeCode>
          </efac:NoticeSubType>
          <efac:Organizations>
            <efac:Organization>
              <efac:Company>
                <cbc:WebsiteURI>http://www.sykehusinnkjop.no</cbc:WebsiteURI>
                <cac:PartyIdentification>
                  <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
                </cac:PartyIdentification>
                
                <cac:PartyName>
                  <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">SYKEHUSINNKJØP HF</cbc:Name>
                </cac:PartyName>
                <cac:PostalAddress>
                  <cbc:StreetName>Postboks 40</cbc:StreetName>
                  <cbc:Department>Sykehusinnkjøp HF, div Sør-Øst</cbc:Department>
                  <cbc:CityName>VADSØ</cbc:CityName>
                  <cbc:PostalZone>9811</cbc:PostalZone>
                  <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO073</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
                  <cac:Country>
                    <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
                  </cac:Country>
                </cac:PostalAddress>
                <cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                  <cbc:CompanyID schemeID="002">916879067</cbc:CompanyID>
                </cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                <cac:Contact>
                  <cbc:Name>Postmottak Sykehusinnkjøp</cbc:Name>
                  <cbc:Telephone>+47 78950700</cbc:Telephone>
                  <cbc:ElectronicMail>post@sykehusinnkjop.no</cbc:ElectronicMail>
                </cac:Contact>
              </efac:Company>
            </efac:Organization>
            <efac:Organization>
              <efac:Company>
                <cac:PartyIdentification>
                  <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
                </cac:PartyIdentification>
                
                <cac:PartyName>
                  <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Indre og Østre Finnmark tingrett</cbc:Name>
                </cac:PartyName>
                <cac:PostalAddress>
                  <cbc:CityName>Vadsø</cbc:CityName>
                  <cbc:PostalZone>9811</cbc:PostalZone>
                  <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO073</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
                  <cac:Country>
                    <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
                  </cac:Country>
                </cac:PostalAddress>
                <cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                  <cbc:CompanyID schemeID="002">926722840</cbc:CompanyID>
                </cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                <cac:Contact>
                  <cbc:Telephone>78011700</cbc:Telephone>
                  <cbc:ElectronicMail>indre.og.ostre.finnmark.tingrett@domstol.no</cbc:ElectronicMail>
                </cac:Contact>
              </efac:Company>
            </efac:Organization>
          </efac:Organizations>
        <efac:Publication><efbc:NoticePublicationID schemeName="ojs-notice-id">00368017-2025</efbc:NoticePublicationID><efbc:GazetteID schemeName="ojs-id">108/2025</efbc:GazetteID><efbc:PublicationDate>2025-06-06+02:00</efbc:PublicationDate></efac:Publication></efext:EformsExtension>
      </ext:ExtensionContent>
    </ext:UBLExtension>
  </ext:UBLExtensions>
  <cbc:UBLVersionID>2.3</cbc:UBLVersionID>
  <cbc:CustomizationID>eforms-sdk-1.13</cbc:CustomizationID>
  <cbc:ID schemeName="notice-id">d0f73ca2-badc-44f0-b8cd-80f663056350</cbc:ID>
  <cbc:ContractFolderID>c680047c-191f-4030-8c2b-a117b7e6da98</cbc:ContractFolderID>
  <cbc:IssueDate>2025-06-05+00:00</cbc:IssueDate>
  <cbc:IssueTime>08:08:06+00:00</cbc:IssueTime>
  <cbc:VersionID>01</cbc:VersionID>
  <cbc:RegulatoryDomain>32014L0024</cbc:RegulatoryDomain>
  <cbc:NoticeTypeCode listName="competition">cn-standard</cbc:NoticeTypeCode>
  <cbc:NoticeLanguageCode>ENG</cbc:NoticeLanguageCode>
  
  <cac:ContractingParty>
    <cac:ContractingPartyType>
      <cbc:PartyTypeCode listName="buyer-legal-type">body-pl</cbc:PartyTypeCode>
    </cac:ContractingPartyType>
    <cac:ContractingActivity>
      <cbc:ActivityTypeCode listName="authority-activity">health</cbc:ActivityTypeCode>
    </cac:ContractingActivity>
    <cac:Party>
      <cac:PartyIdentification>
        <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
      </cac:PartyIdentification>
    </cac:Party>
  </cac:ContractingParty>
  <cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:ProcurementLegislationDocumentReference>
      <cbc:ID>Anskaffelsesforskriften</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:DocumentDescription languageID="ENG">Procurement above the EEA threshold value.</cbc:DocumentDescription>
    </cac:ProcurementLegislationDocumentReference>
    <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-corrpt</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a enforceable verdict has been convicted of corruption by a verdict handed down not more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Corruption as defined in Article 3 of the Convention on Combating Corruption, Involving European Communities or European Union Member States (EUT C 195 of 25.6.1997, s. 1), and in Article 2, point 1, in the Council ́s framework decision 2003/568/RIA of 22 July 2003 on combating corruption in the private sector (EUT L 192 of 31.7.2003,  p. 54). This rejection reason also includes corruption as defined in national law for the contracting authority or supplier.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-fraud</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, at the time a legally convicted of fraud has been convicted of fraud by a verdict handed down not more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Fraud included in Article 1 of the Convention on protection of the Financial Interests of the European Communities (EFT C 316 of 27.11.1995, p. 48).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-laund</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of money laundering or financing terrorism by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Money laundering or financing terrorism As defined in Article 1 of the European Parliament and Council Directive 2005/60/EF of 26 October 2005 on preventive measures against the use of the financial system for money laundering and financing terrorism (EUT L 309 of 25.11.2005, p. 15).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-part</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, at the time a legally convicted verdict of participation in a criminal organisation by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Participation in a criminal organisation as defined in Article 2 of the Council ́s framework decision 2008/841/RIA of 24 October 2008 on control of organised crime (EUT L 300 of 11.11.2008, p. 42)</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-terror</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body, or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of acts of terrorism or criminal acts connected to terrorist activities by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Acts of terrorism or criminal acts relating to terrorist activity as defined in Article 1 and 3 of the Council ́s framework decision 2002/475/RIA of 13 June 2002 on combating terrorism (EFT L 164, af 22.6.2002, p. 3). This rejection reason also includes incitement to, participation or attempts to commit such actions as included in Article 4 in the mentioned framework decision.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-traffick</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of child labour and other forms of human trafficking by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Child labour and other forms of human trafficking as defined in Article 2 of the European Parliament and council directive 2011/36/EU of 5. 1 April 2011 on the prevention and control of human trafficking and the protection of its victims and for compensation of the Council ́s framework decision 2002/629/RIA (EUT L 101 of 15.4.2011, p. 1).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-bre-env-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer aware of breaches of environmental provisions as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents or Article 18 (2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-bre-lab-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer aware of breaches of provisions on working conditions as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents or Article 18 (2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-bre-soc-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer aware of breaches of provisions on social conditions as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents or Article 18 (2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-distortion</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer entered into agreement(s) with other tenderers with the intention of turning the competition?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-misconduct</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer committed serious errors in professional practice? If relevant, see the definitions in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-misrepresent</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Have the tenderer:a) given grossly incorrect information when notifying the information required to verify that there is no basis for rejection, or of the qualification requirements being met,b) failed to provide such information,c) subject to immediately submitting the supporting documents requested by the Contracting Authority, ord) improperly affecting the Contracting Authority's decision process to acquire confidential information that could give this an unlawful advantage in connection with competition, or negligently has given misleading information that can have a significant influence on decisions on rejection, selection or award?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-partic-confl</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Are tenderers aware of a conflict of interest as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-prep-confl</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer or an entity associated with the supplier advised the contracting authority or in another way been involved in the planning of the competition?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-sanction</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer committed significant breaches of contract in connection with the fulfilment of a previous public contract, a previous contract with a public contracting authority or a previous concession contract, where the breach has led to the cancellation of the contract, compensation or other similar sanctions?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-natl-bre-nat-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The contracting authority shall state that in Norway there are national rejection reasons. These shall be described in the procurement documents. Tenderers must respond to whether they are in one or more of the situations described in the national rejection reasons. Will the purely national rejection reasons, as stated in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents, apply?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-pmt-bre-ssc</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Have tenderers failed to fulfil all their social security obligations in the country where they are established and in their member state, if this is a different country than what he is established in?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-pmt-bre-tax</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer not fulfilled his tax and duty obligations in the country in which he is established, and in the contracting authority's member state, if this is a different country than what he is established in?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-as-susp</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-bankr</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer in a bankruptcy situation? Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-cred-arran</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the supplier in a situation where he has been forced debt arrangement?  Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-insolvency</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer in an insolvency situation? Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-liq-admin</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the supplier in a situation where he has been forced debt arrangement?  Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
    </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
    <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-grounds-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
    </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
  </cac:TenderingTerms>
  <cac:TenderingProcess>
    
    <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The Hospital in Vestfold shall procure 2 complete ultrasound apparatus with probes and software, for use in pregnancy and gynaecological. The contracting authority requests the following options: 8 apparatuses, equivalent to the main delivery to the Hospital in Vestfold10 apparatuses, equivalent to the main delivery to the Hospitals in Helse Sør-Øst and Sykehusbygg. The picture quality and user friendliness will be emphasised in the evaluation of the product. The procurement shall be carried out for the replacement of the old equipment. See the Requirement Specifications and the Price Form for further details.</cbc:Description>
    <cbc:ProcedureCode listName="procurement-procedure-type">open</cbc:ProcedureCode>
    <cac:ProcessJustification>
      <cbc:ProcessReasonCode listName="accelerated-procedure">false</cbc:ProcessReasonCode>
    </cac:ProcessJustification>
  </cac:TenderingProcess>
  <cac:ProcurementProject>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025/49408</cbc:ID>
    
    <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Ultrasound for gyn at The Hospital in Vestfold HF</cbc:Name>
    
    <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The Hospital in Vestfold HF shall procure 2 mid-range ultrasound apparatuses for pregnancy and gynaecological outpatient clinics. In addition options are wanted for Vestfold Hospital, The Hospital in Helse Sør-Øst and Sykehusbygg.</cbc:Description>
    <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">supplies</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
    <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">33112200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
    <cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:Address>
        <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO093</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
        <cac:Country>
          <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
        </cac:Country>
      </cac:Address>
    </cac:RealizedLocation>
  </cac:ProcurementProject>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0000</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-trade</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers are registered in a company register or a trade register in the member state in which the tenderer is established. As described in annex XI of directive 2014/24/EU; suppliers from certain member states may have to fulfil other requirements in the mentioned annex.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Regarding any other economic and financial requirements that have been stated in the notice or in the procurement documents, the tenderer declares that:
Minimum qualification requirements
Tenderers must have sufficient economic and financial capacity to fulfil the contractual obligations. Economic and financial capacity means that the tenderer fulfils the following requirement: Credit rating equivalent to A or better, measured on AAA Soliditet's scale - or equivalent score from another reputable rating company. Documentation requirement: The contracting authority will assess the tenderer's fulfilment of the qualification requirement in the following manner: - Credit rating, not older than 6 months, and which is based on the last known accounting figures. If a tenderer has a justifiable reason for not submitting the documentation that the contracting authority has required, the tenderer can prove its economic and financial capacity by any other document, including a commitment statement, parent company guarantee, bank guarantee, etc. The contracting authority reserves the right to obtain a credit report in www.soliditet.no (provided by Bisnode Credit AS/Dun &amp;amp; Bradstreet) in order to verify that the Tenderer has sufficient economic and financial capacity to fulfil the contractual obligations.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-qu-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Can tenderers submit certificates issued by independent bodies that document that the tenderer fulfils the stated quality assurance standards, including universal design requirements?
Minimum qualification requirements
The tenderer/manufacturer shall have an certified quality assurance system. Documentation requirement: Certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer's/manufacturer's quality system is certified. The certificate shall show that the quality system is based on relevant European standard series, for example ISO 9001. The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. The contracting authority will accept other documentation for an equivalent quality system if the tenderer is unable to obtain such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures correspond to the requested quality standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-env-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer able to submit certificates issued by independent bodies as documentation that the tenderer fulfils the stated environmental management systems or standards?
Minimum qualification requirements
The tenderer/manufacturer shall be third party certified for environmental management, in the form of EMAS, ISO 14001, Miljøfyrtårn or equivalent environmental management standard. Documentation requirement: Licence number for EMAS, ISO 14001 or The Eco-Lighthouse, issued by independent bodies. The certification shall be valid from the commencement of the contract and during the entire contract period. If the tenderer/manufacturer shall be re-certified during the contract period, a new valid certificate shall be sent to Sykehusinnkjøp HF as soon as it is ready and without request. The contracting authority will also accept other equivalent certificates issued by bodies in other EEA states. The contracting authority will also accept other documentation for equivalent environmental management measures if the tenderer is unable to obtain such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures are equivalent to the requested quality assurance standards or environmental management systems or standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:FundingProgramCode listName="eu-funded">no-eu-funds</cbc:FundingProgramCode>
      <cbc:MultipleTendersCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:MultipleTendersCode>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <ext:UBLExtensions>
          <ext:UBLExtension>
            <ext:ExtensionContent>
              <efext:EformsExtension>
                <efac:OfficialLanguages>
                  <cac:Language>
                    <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
                  </cac:Language>
                </efac:OfficialLanguages>
              </efext:EformsExtension>
            </ext:ExtensionContent>
          </ext:UBLExtension>
        </ext:UBLExtensions>
        <cbc:ID>258609943</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://permalink.mercell.com/258609943.aspx</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="esignature-submission">true</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://permalink.mercell.com/258609943.aspx</cbc:EndpointID>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="MONTH">6</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">10 day waiting period.</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealInformationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealInformationParty>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
      <cac:PostAwardProcess>
        <cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>
        <cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>
      </cac:PostAwardProcess>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-08-04+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-07-03+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
      <cac:OpenTenderEvent>
        <cbc:OccurrenceDate>2025-08-04+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceDate>
        <cbc:OccurrenceTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceTime>
      </cac:OpenTenderEvent>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025/49408</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Ultrasound for gyn at The Hospital in Vestfold HF</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The Hospital in Vestfold HF shall procure 2 mid-range ultrasound apparatuses for pregnancy and gynaecological outpatient clinics. In addition options are wanted for Vestfold Hospital, The Hospital in Helse Sør-Øst and Sykehusbygg.</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">supplies</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">33112200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO093</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
          <cac:Country>
            <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
          </cac:Country>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="MONTH">120</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
</ContractNotice>