<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><ContractNotice xmlns="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:ContractNotice-2" xmlns:cac="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonAggregateComponents-2" xmlns:cbc="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonBasicComponents-2" xmlns:efac="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extension-aggregate-components/1" xmlns:efbc="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extension-basic-components/1" xmlns:efext="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extensions/1" xmlns:ext="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonExtensionComponents-2">
  <ext:UBLExtensions>
    <ext:UBLExtension>
      <ext:ExtensionContent>
        <efext:EformsExtension>
          <efbc:TransmissionDate>2025-06-05+00:00</efbc:TransmissionDate>
          <efbc:TransmissionTime>10:37:58+00:00</efbc:TransmissionTime>
          <efac:NoticeSubType>
            <cbc:SubTypeCode listName="notice-subtype">16</cbc:SubTypeCode>
          </efac:NoticeSubType>
          <efac:Organizations>
            <efac:Organization>
              <efac:Company>
                <cbc:WebsiteURI>https://FMA.NO</cbc:WebsiteURI>
                <cac:PartyIdentification>
                  <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
                </cac:PartyIdentification>
                
                <cac:PartyName>
                  <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">FORSVARSMATERIELL</cbc:Name>
                </cac:PartyName>
                <cac:PostalAddress>
                  <cbc:StreetName>Grev Wedels plass 1</cbc:StreetName>
                  <cbc:CityName>OSLO</cbc:CityName>
                  <cbc:PostalZone>0151</cbc:PostalZone>
                  <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO081</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
                  <cac:Country>
                    <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
                  </cac:Country>
                </cac:PostalAddress>
                <cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                  <cbc:CompanyID schemeID="002">916075855</cbc:CompanyID>
                </cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                <cac:Contact>
                  <cbc:Name>Mariann Døhl Martinsen</cbc:Name>
                  <cbc:Telephone>92218145</cbc:Telephone>
                  <cbc:ElectronicMail>marianmartins@mil.no</cbc:ElectronicMail>
                </cac:Contact>
              </efac:Company>
            </efac:Organization>
            <efac:Organization>
              <efac:Company>
                <cac:PartyIdentification>
                  <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
                </cac:PartyIdentification>
                
                <cac:PartyName>
                  <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Oslo Tingrett</cbc:Name>
                </cac:PartyName>
                <cac:PostalAddress>
                  <cbc:CityName>Oslo</cbc:CityName>
                  <cbc:PostalZone>0164</cbc:PostalZone>
                  <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO081</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
                  <cac:Country>
                    <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
                  </cac:Country>
                </cac:PostalAddress>
                <cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                  <cbc:CompanyID schemeID="002">926 725 939</cbc:CompanyID>
                </cac:PartyLegalEntity>
              </efac:Company>
            </efac:Organization>
          </efac:Organizations>
        <efac:Publication><efbc:NoticePublicationID schemeName="ojs-notice-id">00365530-2025</efbc:NoticePublicationID><efbc:GazetteID schemeName="ojs-id">108/2025</efbc:GazetteID><efbc:PublicationDate>2025-06-06+02:00</efbc:PublicationDate></efac:Publication></efext:EformsExtension>
      </ext:ExtensionContent>
    </ext:UBLExtension>
  </ext:UBLExtensions>
  <cbc:UBLVersionID>2.3</cbc:UBLVersionID>
  <cbc:CustomizationID>eforms-sdk-1.13</cbc:CustomizationID>
  <cbc:ID schemeName="notice-id">8fc2d39c-9964-43f1-99b4-9cd64bc82dc7</cbc:ID>
  <cbc:ContractFolderID>62853ebb-81f9-4bc7-a148-666da6e64584</cbc:ContractFolderID>
  <cbc:IssueDate>2025-06-05+00:00</cbc:IssueDate>
  <cbc:IssueTime>10:19:13+00:00</cbc:IssueTime>
  <cbc:VersionID>01</cbc:VersionID>
  <cbc:RequestedPublicationDate>2025-06-06Z</cbc:RequestedPublicationDate>
  <cbc:RegulatoryDomain>32014L0024</cbc:RegulatoryDomain>
  <cbc:NoticeTypeCode listName="competition">cn-standard</cbc:NoticeTypeCode>
  <cbc:NoticeLanguageCode>ENG</cbc:NoticeLanguageCode>
  
  <cac:ContractingParty>
    <cac:ContractingPartyType>
      <cbc:PartyTypeCode listName="buyer-legal-type">def-cont</cbc:PartyTypeCode>
    </cac:ContractingPartyType>
    <cac:ContractingActivity>
      <cbc:ActivityTypeCode listName="authority-activity">defence</cbc:ActivityTypeCode>
    </cac:ContractingActivity>
    <cac:Party>
      <cac:PartyIdentification>
        <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
      </cac:PartyIdentification>
    </cac:Party>
  </cac:ContractingParty>
  <cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:ProcurementLegislationDocumentReference>
      <cbc:ID>Anskaffelsesforskriften</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:DocumentDescription languageID="ENG">Act 17 June 2016 no. 73 on public procurements (the Public Procurement Act - LOA) and the regulations of 12 August 2016 no. 974 on public procurements (procurement regulations - FOA). 
The procedure 'open tender contest' in accordance with the Public Procurement Regulations § 13-1(1).</cbc:DocumentDescription>
    </cac:ProcurementLegislationDocumentReference>
    <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-corrpt</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a enforceable verdict has been convicted of corruption by a verdict handed down not more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Corruption as defined in Article 3 of the Convention on Combating Corruption, Involving European Communities or European Union Member States (EUT C 195 of 25.6.1997, s. 1), and in Article 2, point 1, in the Council ́s framework decision 2003/568/RIA of 22 July 2003 on combating corruption in the private sector (EUT L 192 of 31.7.2003,  p. 54). This rejection reason also includes corruption as defined in national law for the contracting authority or supplier.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-fraud</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, at the time a legally convicted of fraud has been convicted of fraud by a verdict handed down not more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Fraud included in Article 1 of the Convention on protection of the Financial Interests of the European Communities (EFT C 316 of 27.11.1995, p. 48).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-laund</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of money laundering or financing terrorism by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Money laundering or financing terrorism As defined in Article 1 of the European Parliament and Council Directive 2005/60/EF of 26 October 2005 on preventive measures against the use of the financial system for money laundering and financing terrorism (EUT L 309 of 25.11.2005, p. 15).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-part</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, at the time a legally convicted verdict of participation in a criminal organisation by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Participation in a criminal organisation as defined in Article 2 of the Council ́s framework decision 2008/841/RIA of 24 October 2008 on control of organised crime (EUT L 300 of 11.11.2008, p. 42)</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-terror</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body, or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of acts of terrorism or criminal acts connected to terrorist activities by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Acts of terrorism or criminal acts relating to terrorist activity as defined in Article 1 and 3 of the Council ́s framework decision 2002/475/RIA of 13 June 2002 on combating terrorism (EFT L 164, af 22.6.2002, p. 3). This rejection reason also includes incitement to, participation or attempts to commit such actions as included in Article 4 in the mentioned framework decision.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-traffick</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of child labour and other forms of human trafficking by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Child labour and other forms of human trafficking as defined in Article 2 of the European Parliament and council directive 2011/36/EU of 5. 1 April 2011 on the prevention and control of human trafficking and the protection of its victims and for compensation of the Council ́s framework decision 2002/629/RIA (EUT L 101 of 15.4.2011, p. 1).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-bre-lab-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer aware of breaches of provisions on working conditions as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents or Article 18 (2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-misconduct</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer committed serious errors in professional practice? If relevant, see the definitions in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-natl-bre-nat-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The contracting authority shall state that in Norway there are national rejection reasons. These shall be described in the procurement documents. Tenderers must respond to whether they are in one or more of the situations described in the national rejection reasons. Will the purely national rejection reasons, as stated in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents, apply?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-pmt-bre-ssc</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Have tenderers failed to fulfil all their social security obligations in the country where they are established and in their member state, if this is a different country than what he is established in?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-pmt-bre-tax</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer not fulfilled his tax and duty obligations in the country in which he is established, and in the contracting authority's member state, if this is a different country than what he is established in?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
    </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
    <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-grounds-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
    </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
  </cac:TenderingTerms>
  <cac:TenderingProcess>
    
    <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The contract includes the following: The procurement shall cover the Defence sector's need for software licences and software maintenance, for existing and future licences within the stated function areas, cf. Part 2 SSA-K Annex 1. Support services are also included, to the degree that they are included in rights holders or the tenderer ́s offered software maintenance.  The procurement concerns licenses within the infrastructure category from the following rights holders/manufacturers: Red Hat, Hornetsecurity (previously Altaro), Teradici (HP Anyware), TrendMicro, Citrix, Nvidia (Nvidia Subscription), SecureCRT (VanDyke Software), Nagios, WhatsUp Gold, Isode and Oracle Forms and Reports (Weblogic).   Tenderers can only deliver for entire, not parts of the procurement.</cbc:Description>
    <cbc:ProcedureCode listName="procurement-procedure-type">open</cbc:ProcedureCode>
    <cac:ProcessJustification>
      <cbc:ProcessReasonCode listName="accelerated-procedure">false</cbc:ProcessReasonCode>
    </cac:ProcessJustification>
  </cac:TenderingProcess>
  <cac:ProcurementProject>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025015718</cbc:ID>
    
    <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Procurement of a framework agreement for software licences and software maintenance - Infrastructure</cbc:Name>
    
    <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The contract includes the following: The procurement shall cover the Defence sector's need for software licences and software maintenance, for existing and future licences within the stated function areas, cf. Part 2 SSA-K Annex 1. Support services are also included, to the degree that they are included in rights holders or the tenderer ́s offered software maintenance.  The procurement concerns licenses within the infrastructure category from the following rights holders/manufacturers: Solidworks, Autocad, Fotoware, Classify for Outlook, Clarify/Ifinger, Mindmanager, Sparx Enterprise Architect, Articulate, Slack,  Miro og Figma.   

  Tenderers can only deliver for entire, not parts of the procurement.</cbc:Description>
    <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
    <cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
      <cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount currencyID="NOK">56000000.00</cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount>
    </cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
    <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72268000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">48000000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">48620000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:Address>
        <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO084</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
        <cac:Country>
          <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
        </cac:Country>
      </cac:Address>
    </cac:RealizedLocation>
  </cac:ProcurementProject>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0000</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-prof</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers shall be a legally established company, registered in a trade or business register in the country of origin or establishment.   Valid registration certificate. 
Norwegian tenderers:
-Registration
Foreign tenderers:
- Certificate of registration</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers shall submit a tax certificate for VAT and a tax certificate.
 Norwegian tenderers: 
•Tax certificate for VAT and tax certificate for tax.

Foreign tenderers:
Documentation showing equivalent tax certificate for VAT and tax certificate.

The certificates must not be older than six months calculated from the deadline for receipt of tenders.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers shall have the necessary economic and financial capacity to carry out the contract.   The tenderer's annual report from the last three years, as well as a credit rating from a certified credit rating company based on the last fiscal figures. The credit rating must not be more than three months old.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-mgmt-qual</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The tenderer shall be able to deliver on the published portfolio in its entirety. This includes the Contracting Authority ́s existing software included in the notice and other functionality within the same product family. Tenderers and any sub-suppliers must document the necessary dealer status for the named rightful owners.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-mgmt-qual</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers shall have sufficient capacity to handle customers with a large number of employees and complexity. - Tenderers must provide two customer references that show that they have handled large customers, as regards both the number of employees (minimum 5,000 employees) and similar complexity. 
- Tenderers must provide contact data, in addition to a short description of the delivery size and content.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-mgmt-qual</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The tenderer ́s proposed customer teams shall have at least 2 employees who have worked on the published portfolio/similar software, in addition to having worked with customers of an equivalent size and complexity. Tenderers must present a proposed reception apparatus/customer team for the execution of this delivery.  
- Tenderers must describe the customer team ́s experience, competence and capacity.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-mgmt-qual</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers shall have a good quality management system. 
 - If the tenderer is certified in accordance with ISO 9001 or equivalent standard, a copy of a valid certificate prepared by an accreditation body that certifies that the tenderer ́s quality management system is in accordance with such a standard.
- If a tenderer is not certified in accordance with such a standard, a description of the tenderer's quality assurance system.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-mgmt-qual</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers shall have a good information security management system.  - If the tenderer is certified in accordance with ISO 27001 or equivalent standard, a copy of a valid certificate prepared by an accreditation body that certifies that the tenderer's management system is in accordance with such a standard.
- If the tenderer is not certified in accordance with such a standard, a description of the tenderer's management system for information security.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-mgmt-qual</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers shall have a good environmental management system.  - If the tenderer is certified in accordance with ISO 14001 or equivalent standard, a copy of a valid certificate prepared by an accreditation body that certifies that the tenderer's environmental management system is in accordance with such a standard.

- If the tenderer is not certified in accordance with such a standard, a description of the tenderer's environmental management system.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:FundingProgramCode listName="eu-funded">no-eu-funds</cbc:FundingProgramCode>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <ext:UBLExtensions>
          <ext:UBLExtension>
            <ext:ExtensionContent>
              <efext:EformsExtension>
                <efac:OfficialLanguages>
                  <cac:Language>
                    <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
                  </cac:Language>
                </efac:OfficialLanguages>
              </efext:EformsExtension>
            </ext:ExtensionContent>
          </ext:UBLExtension>
        </ext:UBLExtensions>
        <cbc:ID>258840335</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://permalink.mercell.com/258840335.aspx</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">allowed</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="esignature-submission">false</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://permalink.mercell.com/258840335.aspx</cbc:EndpointID>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="MONTH">6</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">In accordance with the regulations.</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
      <cac:PostAwardProcess>
        <cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>
        <cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>
      </cac:PostAwardProcess>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-06-26+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
      <cac:OpenTenderEvent>
        <cbc:OccurrenceDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceDate>
        <cbc:OccurrenceTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceTime>
      </cac:OpenTenderEvent>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:FrameworkAgreement>
        <cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>10</cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>
        
        <cbc:Justification languageID="ENG">Normal varighet</cbc:Justification>
      </cac:FrameworkAgreement>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">fa-wo-rc</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025015718</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Procurement of a framework agreement for software licences and software maintenance - Infrastructure</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The contract includes the following: The procurement shall cover the Defence sector's need for software licences and software maintenance, for existing and future licences within the stated function areas, cf. Part 2 SSA-K Annex 1. Support services are also included, to the degree that they are included in rights holders or the tenderer ́s offered software maintenance.  The procurement concerns licenses within the infrastructure category from the following rights holders/manufacturers: Solidworks, Autocad, Fotoware, Classify for Outlook, Clarify/Ifinger, Mindmanager, Sparx Enterprise Architect, Articulate, Slack,  Miro og Figma.   

  Tenderers can only deliver for entire, not parts of the procurement.</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
        <cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount currencyID="NOK">56000000.00</cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount>
      </cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72268000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">48000000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">48620000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO084</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
          <cac:Country>
            <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
          </cac:Country>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:StartDate>2025-08-13Z</cbc:StartDate>
        <cbc:EndDate>2029-08-15Z</cbc:EndDate>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
</ContractNotice>