<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><ContractNotice xmlns="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:ContractNotice-2" xmlns:cac="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonAggregateComponents-2" xmlns:cbc="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonBasicComponents-2" xmlns:efac="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extension-aggregate-components/1" xmlns:efbc="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extension-basic-components/1" xmlns:efext="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extensions/1" xmlns:ext="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonExtensionComponents-2">
  <ext:UBLExtensions>
    <ext:UBLExtension>
      <ext:ExtensionContent>
        <efext:EformsExtension>
          <efbc:TransmissionDate>2025-06-05+00:00</efbc:TransmissionDate>
          <efbc:TransmissionTime>06:54:47+00:00</efbc:TransmissionTime>
          <efac:NoticeSubType>
            <cbc:SubTypeCode listName="notice-subtype">16</cbc:SubTypeCode>
          </efac:NoticeSubType>
          <efac:Organizations>
            <efac:Organization>
              <efac:Company>
                <cbc:WebsiteURI>http://www.sykehusinnkjop.no</cbc:WebsiteURI>
                <cac:PartyIdentification>
                  <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
                </cac:PartyIdentification>
                
                <cac:PartyName>
                  <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">SYKEHUSINNKJØP HF</cbc:Name>
                </cac:PartyName>
                <cac:PostalAddress>
                  <cbc:StreetName>Postboks 40</cbc:StreetName>
                  <cbc:CityName>VADSØ</cbc:CityName>
                  <cbc:PostalZone>9811</cbc:PostalZone>
                  <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO073</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
                  <cac:Country>
                    <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
                  </cac:Country>
                </cac:PostalAddress>
                <cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                  <cbc:CompanyID schemeID="002">916879067</cbc:CompanyID>
                </cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                <cac:Contact>
                  <cbc:Name>Postmottak Sykehusinnkjøp</cbc:Name>
                  <cbc:Telephone>+47 78950700</cbc:Telephone>
                  <cbc:ElectronicMail>post@sykehusinnkjop.no</cbc:ElectronicMail>
                </cac:Contact>
              </efac:Company>
            </efac:Organization>
            <efac:Organization>
              <efac:Company>
                <cac:PartyIdentification>
                  <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
                </cac:PartyIdentification>
                
                <cac:PartyName>
                  <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Indre og Østre Finnmark tingrett</cbc:Name>
                </cac:PartyName>
                <cac:PostalAddress>
                  <cbc:CityName>Vadsø</cbc:CityName>
                  <cbc:PostalZone>9800</cbc:PostalZone>
                  <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO073</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
                  <cac:Country>
                    <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
                  </cac:Country>
                </cac:PostalAddress>
                <cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                  <cbc:CompanyID schemeID="002">926 722 840</cbc:CompanyID>
                </cac:PartyLegalEntity>
              </efac:Company>
            </efac:Organization>
          </efac:Organizations>
        <efac:Publication><efbc:NoticePublicationID schemeName="ojs-notice-id">00366861-2025</efbc:NoticePublicationID><efbc:GazetteID schemeName="ojs-id">108/2025</efbc:GazetteID><efbc:PublicationDate>2025-06-06+02:00</efbc:PublicationDate></efac:Publication></efext:EformsExtension>
      </ext:ExtensionContent>
    </ext:UBLExtension>
  </ext:UBLExtensions>
  <cbc:UBLVersionID>2.3</cbc:UBLVersionID>
  <cbc:CustomizationID>eforms-sdk-1.13</cbc:CustomizationID>
  <cbc:ID schemeName="notice-id">a3aab3ff-d7a1-427d-8f30-bcf18d5cd6e8</cbc:ID>
  <cbc:ContractFolderID>a363b6d0-9cb4-4e5b-be5f-28084d91b026</cbc:ContractFolderID>
  <cbc:IssueDate>2025-06-05+00:00</cbc:IssueDate>
  <cbc:IssueTime>06:44:01+00:00</cbc:IssueTime>
  <cbc:VersionID>01</cbc:VersionID>
  <cbc:RegulatoryDomain>32014L0024</cbc:RegulatoryDomain>
  <cbc:NoticeTypeCode listName="competition">cn-standard</cbc:NoticeTypeCode>
  <cbc:NoticeLanguageCode>ENG</cbc:NoticeLanguageCode>
  
  <cac:ContractingParty>
    <cac:ContractingPartyType>
      <cbc:PartyTypeCode listName="buyer-legal-type">pub-undert</cbc:PartyTypeCode>
    </cac:ContractingPartyType>
    <cac:ContractingActivity>
      <cbc:ActivityTypeCode listName="authority-activity">health</cbc:ActivityTypeCode>
    </cac:ContractingActivity>
    <cac:Party>
      <cac:PartyIdentification>
        <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
      </cac:PartyIdentification>
    </cac:Party>
  </cac:ContractingParty>
  <cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:ProcurementLegislationDocumentReference>
      <cbc:ID>Anskaffelsesforskriften</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:DocumentDescription languageID="ENG">Public Procurements Act (the Procurement Act)</cbc:DocumentDescription>
    </cac:ProcurementLegislationDocumentReference>
    <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-corrpt</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a enforceable verdict has been convicted of corruption by a verdict handed down not more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Corruption as defined in Article 3 of the Convention on Combating Corruption, Involving European Communities or European Union Member States (EUT C 195 of 25.6.1997, s. 1), and in Article 2, point 1, in the Council ́s framework decision 2003/568/RIA of 22 July 2003 on combating corruption in the private sector (EUT L 192 of 31.7.2003,  p. 54). This rejection reason also includes corruption as defined in national law for the contracting authority or supplier.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-fraud</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, at the time a legally convicted of fraud has been convicted of fraud by a verdict handed down not more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Fraud included in Article 1 of the Convention on protection of the Financial Interests of the European Communities (EFT C 316 of 27.11.1995, p. 48).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-laund</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of money laundering or financing terrorism by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Money laundering or financing terrorism As defined in Article 1 of the European Parliament and Council Directive 2005/60/EF of 26 October 2005 on preventive measures against the use of the financial system for money laundering and financing terrorism (EUT L 309 of 25.11.2005, p. 15).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-part</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, at the time a legally convicted verdict of participation in a criminal organisation by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Participation in a criminal organisation as defined in Article 2 of the Council ́s framework decision 2008/841/RIA of 24 October 2008 on control of organised crime (EUT L 300 of 11.11.2008, p. 42)</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-terror</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body, or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of acts of terrorism or criminal acts connected to terrorist activities by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Acts of terrorism or criminal acts relating to terrorist activity as defined in Article 1 and 3 of the Council ́s framework decision 2002/475/RIA of 13 June 2002 on combating terrorism (EFT L 164, af 22.6.2002, p. 3). This rejection reason also includes incitement to, participation or attempts to commit such actions as included in Article 4 in the mentioned framework decision.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-traffick</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of child labour and other forms of human trafficking by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Child labour and other forms of human trafficking as defined in Article 2 of the European Parliament and council directive 2011/36/EU of 5. 1 April 2011 on the prevention and control of human trafficking and the protection of its victims and for compensation of the Council ́s framework decision 2002/629/RIA (EUT L 101 of 15.4.2011, p. 1).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-pmt-bre-ssc</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Have tenderers failed to fulfil all their social security obligations in the country where they are established and in their member state, if this is a different country than what he is established in?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-pmt-bre-tax</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer not fulfilled his tax and duty obligations in the country in which he is established, and in the contracting authority's member state, if this is a different country than what he is established in?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
    </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
    <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-grounds-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
    </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
    <cac:LotDistribution>
      <cbc:MaximumLotsAwardedNumeric>9</cbc:MaximumLotsAwardedNumeric>
      <cbc:MaximumLotsSubmittedNumeric>9</cbc:MaximumLotsSubmittedNumeric>
    </cac:LotDistribution>
  </cac:TenderingTerms>
  <cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cbc:ProcedureCode listName="procurement-procedure-type">open</cbc:ProcedureCode>
    <cac:ProcessJustification>
      <cbc:ProcessReasonCode listName="accelerated-procedure">false</cbc:ProcessReasonCode>
    </cac:ProcessJustification>
  </cac:TenderingProcess>
  <cac:ProcurementProject>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2022/11958</cbc:ID>
    
    <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Laundry services for Helse Nord RHF, Helse Møre og Romsdal HF and Helse Fonna HF.</cbc:Name>
    
    <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The objective of the procurement is the hire and laundry of work clothes, patient textiles and flat textiles for the health authorities in Helse Nord, Helse Møre og Romsdal HF and Helse Fonna HF.</cbc:Description>
    <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
    <cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efbc:FrameworkMaximumAmount currencyID="NOK">1218660000</efbc:FrameworkMaximumAmount>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount currencyID="NOK">812440000.00</cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount>
    </cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
    <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98310000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311100</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98312000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:Address>
        <cbc:Region>anyw-cou</cbc:Region>
        <cac:Country>
          <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
        </cac:Country>
      </cac:Address>
    </cac:RealizedLocation>
  </cac:ProcurementProject>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0001</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-trade</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers are registered in a company register or a trade register in the member state in which the tenderer is established. As described in annex XI of directive 2014/24/EU; suppliers from certain member states may have to fulfil other requirements in the mentioned annex.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-to-gen</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The tenderer ́s ("total") annual turnover for the number of financial years requested in the tender notice or in the procurement documents is as follows:
Minimum qualification requirements</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Regarding any other economic and financial requirements that have been stated in the notice or in the procurement documents, the tenderer declares that:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient economic and financial solidity to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Sufficient economic and financial solidity means that the tenderer shall fulfil the following requirements:
• Tenderers are required to have a turnover equivalent to the estimated annual value of the lot(s) that a tender is submitted for.
• Tenderers are required to be "credit worthy without security".

Documentation requirement:
The Contracting Authority will evaluate the Tenderer's fulfilment of the qualification requirements in the following manner:  
• The last submitted Annual Financial Statements with notes including the auditor's statement, possibly income statement and/or the balance sheet for the last year, if it is more than six months since the last annual accounts.
• Tenderers shall, through documentation from a certified credit rating company, document that the tenderer is 'credit worthy without collateral'. The contracting authority reserves the right to verify documentation by carrying out a separate credit rating. The credit rating must not be older than 6 months from the submission date of the tender offer.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-ref-services</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Only for services: In the reference period, the tenderer has carried out the following important goods deliveries of the requested type, or the following important services of the requested type. The contracting authority can require up to three years experience and allow experience from the previous three years to be taken into consideration.
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have experience from deliveries to the health sector.

Documentation requirement:
Description of the tenderer ́s up to 3 relevant deliveries to the health sector. The description shall include a statement of the contract ́s value, date and recipient (name, telephone number and e-mail address).</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-facil-tools</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers can use the following tools, material and technical equipment to carry out the contract:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient ability and capacity to be able to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Tenderers are required to have laundry(s) with sufficient capacity to serve the tenderer/sub-contract(s) that a tender is submitted for. 

If the tenderer is planning to use the existing laundry(s), the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at the existing facilities. 

If the tenderer plans to construct a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at planned facilities, as well as a schedule (including realistic progress from the planning phase to completion).

The requirement also applies for a stand-by laundry system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall document the following:
Description of the technical facilities, including the laundry size and extent. (Max. 1 A4 page).

If a tenderer shall establish a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, a description of the technical facilities shall be presented at the start of the agreement, as outlined above, as well as a copy of the rent or purchase contract connected to the local(s). If the tenderer has not entered into a hire or procurement contract, a copy of the necessary building permits or drawings with information related to geographical locations will also be accepted. In addition a realistic progress plan shall be delivered that outlines progress from planning to completion.

If documentation is submitted for the existing facilities, this will form the basis of the assessment of whether the qualification requirement is fulfilled. 

If documentation is submitted for planned facilities, the description of the technical facilities at the start of the agreement will apply.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-qu-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Can tenderers submit certificates issued by independent bodies that document that the tenderer fulfils the stated quality assurance standards, including universal design requirements?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a certified quality assurance system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s quality system is certified. The certificate shall show that the quality system is based on relevant European standard series, for example ISO 9001. The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. 

The contracting authority will accept other documentation for an equivalent quality system if the tenderer cannot obtain such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures correspond to the requested quality standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-env-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer able to submit certificates issued by independent bodies as documentation that the tenderer fulfils the stated environmental management systems or standards?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a third-party certified environmental management system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s environmental management system is certified. The certificate shall show that the environmental management system is based on relevant European or international standards, for example ISO14001, EMAS, Miljøfyrtårn . 

The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. The contracting authority will accept other documentation for equivalent environmental management measures if the tenderer does not have the possibility to receive such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures are equivalent to the requested environmental management systems or standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:FundingProgramCode listName="eu-funded">no-eu-funds</cbc:FundingProgramCode>
      <cbc:MultipleTendersCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:MultipleTendersCode>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <ext:UBLExtensions>
          <ext:UBLExtension>
            <ext:ExtensionContent>
              <efext:EformsExtension>
                <efac:OfficialLanguages>
                  <cac:Language>
                    <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
                  </cac:Language>
                </efac:OfficialLanguages>
              </efext:EformsExtension>
            </ext:ExtensionContent>
          </ext:UBLExtension>
        </ext:UBLExtensions>
        <cbc:ID>258092886</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="esignature-submission">true</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:EndpointID>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="MONTH">6</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">There will be a waiting period of 10 days after the contract has been awarded.</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealInformationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealInformationParty>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
      <cac:PostAwardProcess>
        <cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>
        <cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>
      </cac:PostAwardProcess>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-06-30+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
      <cac:OpenTenderEvent>
        <cbc:OccurrenceDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceDate>
        <cbc:OccurrenceTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceTime>
      </cac:OpenTenderEvent>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:FrameworkAgreement>
        <cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>100</cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>
        
        <cbc:Justification languageID="ENG">A long duration, and consequently depreciation time, gives laundry suppliers who are not currently able to invest in order to get a contract. The agreement period of 6 years + 2 years will increase the competition.</cbc:Justification>
      </cac:FrameworkAgreement>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">fa-wo-rc</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025/51033</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">DK1 Finnmark Hospital</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Hire and laundry of work clothes, patient clothes and flat textiles for Finnmark Hospital.</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98310000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311100</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98312000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:Region>anyw-cou</cbc:Region>
          <cac:Country>
            <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
          </cac:Country>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:StartDate>2026-05-31Z</cbc:StartDate>
        <cbc:EndDate>2032-05-31Z</cbc:EndDate>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0002</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-trade</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers are registered in a company register or a trade register in the member state in which the tenderer is established. As described in annex XI of directive 2014/24/EU; suppliers from certain member states may have to fulfil other requirements in the mentioned annex.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-to-gen</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The tenderer ́s ("total") annual turnover for the number of financial years requested in the tender notice or in the procurement documents is as follows:
Minimum qualification requirements</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Regarding any other economic and financial requirements that have been stated in the notice or in the procurement documents, the tenderer declares that:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient economic and financial solidity to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Sufficient economic and financial solidity means that the tenderer shall fulfil the following requirements:
• Tenderers are required to have a turnover equivalent to the estimated annual value of the lot(s) that a tender is submitted for.
• Tenderers are required to be "credit worthy without security".

Documentation requirement:
The Contracting Authority will evaluate the Tenderer's fulfilment of the qualification requirements in the following manner:  
• The last submitted Annual Financial Statements with notes including the auditor's statement, possibly income statement and/or the balance sheet for the last year, if it is more than six months since the last annual accounts.
• Tenderers shall, through documentation from a certified credit rating company, document that the tenderer is 'credit worthy without collateral'. The contracting authority reserves the right to verify documentation by carrying out a separate credit rating. The credit rating must not be older than 6 months from the submission date of the tender offer.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-ref-services</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Only for services: In the reference period, the tenderer has carried out the following important goods deliveries of the requested type, or the following important services of the requested type. The contracting authority can require up to three years experience and allow experience from the previous three years to be taken into consideration.
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have experience from deliveries to the health sector.

Documentation requirement:
Description of the tenderer ́s up to 3 relevant deliveries to the health sector. The description shall include a statement of the contract ́s value, date and recipient (name, telephone number and e-mail address).</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-facil-tools</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers can use the following tools, material and technical equipment to carry out the contract:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient ability and capacity to be able to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Tenderers are required to have laundry(s) with sufficient capacity to serve the tenderer/sub-contract(s) that a tender is submitted for. 

If the tenderer is planning to use the existing laundry(s), the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at the existing facilities. 

If the tenderer plans to construct a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at planned facilities, as well as a schedule (including realistic progress from the planning phase to completion).

The requirement also applies for a stand-by laundry system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall document the following:
Description of the technical facilities, including the laundry size and extent. (Max. 1 A4 page).

If a tenderer shall establish a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, a description of the technical facilities shall be presented at the start of the agreement, as outlined above, as well as a copy of the rent or purchase contract connected to the local(s). If the tenderer has not entered into a hire or procurement contract, a copy of the necessary building permits or drawings with information related to geographical locations will also be accepted. In addition a realistic progress plan shall be delivered that outlines progress from planning to completion.

If documentation is submitted for the existing facilities, this will form the basis of the assessment of whether the qualification requirement is fulfilled. 

If documentation is submitted for planned facilities, the description of the technical facilities at the start of the agreement will apply.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-qu-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Can tenderers submit certificates issued by independent bodies that document that the tenderer fulfils the stated quality assurance standards, including universal design requirements?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a certified quality assurance system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s quality system is certified. The certificate shall show that the quality system is based on relevant European standard series, for example ISO 9001. The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. 

The contracting authority will accept other documentation for an equivalent quality system if the tenderer cannot obtain such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures correspond to the requested quality standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-env-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer able to submit certificates issued by independent bodies as documentation that the tenderer fulfils the stated environmental management systems or standards?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a third-party certified environmental management system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s environmental management system is certified. The certificate shall show that the environmental management system is based on relevant European or international standards, for example ISO14001, EMAS, Miljøfyrtårn . 

The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. The contracting authority will accept other documentation for equivalent environmental management measures if the tenderer does not have the possibility to receive such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures are equivalent to the requested environmental management systems or standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:FundingProgramCode listName="eu-funded">no-eu-funds</cbc:FundingProgramCode>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <ext:UBLExtensions>
          <ext:UBLExtension>
            <ext:ExtensionContent>
              <efext:EformsExtension>
                <efac:OfficialLanguages>
                  <cac:Language>
                    <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
                  </cac:Language>
                </efac:OfficialLanguages>
              </efext:EformsExtension>
            </ext:ExtensionContent>
          </ext:UBLExtension>
        </ext:UBLExtensions>
        <cbc:ID>258092942</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="esignature-submission">true</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:EndpointID>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="MONTH">6</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The waiting period is 10 days after the contract has been awarded.</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealInformationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealInformationParty>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
        <cac:MediationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:MediationParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
      <cac:PostAwardProcess>
        <cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>
        <cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>
      </cac:PostAwardProcess>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-06-30+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
      <cac:OpenTenderEvent>
        <cbc:OccurrenceDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceDate>
        <cbc:OccurrenceTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceTime>
      </cac:OpenTenderEvent>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:FrameworkAgreement>
        <cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>100</cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>
        
        <cbc:Justification languageID="ENG">A long duration, and consequently depreciation time, gives laundry suppliers who are not currently able to invest in order to get a contract. The agreement period of 6 years + 2 years will increase the competition.</cbc:Justification>
      </cac:FrameworkAgreement>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">fa-wo-rc</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025/51034</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">DK2 Universitetssykehuset Nord-Norway HF 1, Tromsø</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Hire and laundry of work clothes, patient clothes and flat textiles for the University Hospital of North Norway HF, Tromsø.</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98310000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311100</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98312000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:Region>anyw-cou</cbc:Region>
          <cac:Country>
            <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
          </cac:Country>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:StartDate>2026-05-31Z</cbc:StartDate>
        <cbc:EndDate>2032-05-31Z</cbc:EndDate>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0003</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-trade</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers are registered in a company register or a trade register in the member state in which the tenderer is established. As described in annex XI of directive 2014/24/EU; suppliers from certain member states may have to fulfil other requirements in the mentioned annex.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-to-gen</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The tenderer ́s ("total") annual turnover for the number of financial years requested in the tender notice or in the procurement documents is as follows:
Minimum qualification requirements</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Regarding any other economic and financial requirements that have been stated in the notice or in the procurement documents, the tenderer declares that:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient economic and financial solidity to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Sufficient economic and financial solidity means that the tenderer shall fulfil the following requirements:
• Tenderers are required to have a turnover equivalent to the estimated annual value of the lot(s) that a tender is submitted for.
• Tenderers are required to be "credit worthy without security".

Documentation requirement:
The Contracting Authority will evaluate the Tenderer's fulfilment of the qualification requirements in the following manner:  
• The last submitted Annual Financial Statements with notes including the auditor's statement, possibly income statement and/or the balance sheet for the last year, if it is more than six months since the last annual accounts.
• Tenderers shall, through documentation from a certified credit rating company, document that the tenderer is 'credit worthy without collateral'. The contracting authority reserves the right to verify documentation by carrying out a separate credit rating. The credit rating must not be older than 6 months from the submission date of the tender offer.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-ref-services</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Only for services: In the reference period, the tenderer has carried out the following important goods deliveries of the requested type, or the following important services of the requested type. The contracting authority can require up to three years experience and allow experience from the previous three years to be taken into consideration.
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have experience from deliveries to the health sector.

Documentation requirement:
Description of the tenderer ́s up to 3 relevant deliveries to the health sector. The description shall include a statement of the contract ́s value, date and recipient (name, telephone number and e-mail address).</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-facil-tools</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers can use the following tools, material and technical equipment to carry out the contract:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient ability and capacity to be able to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Tenderers are required to have laundry(s) with sufficient capacity to serve the tenderer/sub-contract(s) that a tender is submitted for. 

If the tenderer is planning to use the existing laundry(s), the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at the existing facilities. 

If the tenderer plans to construct a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at planned facilities, as well as a schedule (including realistic progress from the planning phase to completion).

The requirement also applies for a stand-by laundry system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall document the following:
Description of the technical facilities, including the laundry size and extent. (Max. 1 A4 page).

If a tenderer shall establish a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, a description of the technical facilities shall be presented at the start of the agreement, as outlined above, as well as a copy of the rent or purchase contract connected to the local(s). If the tenderer has not entered into a hire or procurement contract, a copy of the necessary building permits or drawings with information related to geographical locations will also be accepted. In addition a realistic progress plan shall be delivered that outlines progress from planning to completion.

If documentation is submitted for the existing facilities, this will form the basis of the assessment of whether the qualification requirement is fulfilled. 

If documentation is submitted for planned facilities, the description of the technical facilities at the start of the agreement will apply.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-qu-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Can tenderers submit certificates issued by independent bodies that document that the tenderer fulfils the stated quality assurance standards, including universal design requirements?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a certified quality assurance system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s quality system is certified. The certificate shall show that the quality system is based on relevant European standard series, for example ISO 9001. The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. 

The contracting authority will accept other documentation for an equivalent quality system if the tenderer cannot obtain such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures correspond to the requested quality standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-env-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer able to submit certificates issued by independent bodies as documentation that the tenderer fulfils the stated environmental management systems or standards?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a third-party certified environmental management system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s environmental management system is certified. The certificate shall show that the environmental management system is based on relevant European or international standards, for example ISO14001, EMAS, Miljøfyrtårn . 

The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. The contracting authority will accept other documentation for equivalent environmental management measures if the tenderer does not have the possibility to receive such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures are equivalent to the requested environmental management systems or standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:FundingProgramCode listName="eu-funded">no-eu-funds</cbc:FundingProgramCode>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <ext:UBLExtensions>
          <ext:UBLExtension>
            <ext:ExtensionContent>
              <efext:EformsExtension>
                <efac:OfficialLanguages>
                  <cac:Language>
                    <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
                  </cac:Language>
                </efac:OfficialLanguages>
              </efext:EformsExtension>
            </ext:ExtensionContent>
          </ext:UBLExtension>
        </ext:UBLExtensions>
        <cbc:ID>258093006</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="esignature-submission">true</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:EndpointID>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="MONTH">6</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The waiting period is 10 days after the contract has been awarded.</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealInformationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealInformationParty>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
        <cac:MediationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:MediationParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
      <cac:PostAwardProcess>
        <cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>
        <cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>
      </cac:PostAwardProcess>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-06-30+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
      <cac:OpenTenderEvent>
        <cbc:OccurrenceDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceDate>
        <cbc:OccurrenceTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceTime>
      </cac:OpenTenderEvent>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:FrameworkAgreement>
        <cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>100</cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>
        
        <cbc:Justification languageID="ENG">A long duration, and consequently depreciation time, gives laundry suppliers who are not currently able to invest in order to get a contract. The agreement period of 6 years + 2 years will increase the competition.</cbc:Justification>
      </cac:FrameworkAgreement>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">fa-wo-rc</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025/51035</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">DK3 Universitetssykehuset Nord-Norway HF 2, Harstad og Narvik</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Hire and laundry of work clothes, patient clothing and linens for the University Hospital of North Norway HF, Harstad and Narvik.</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98310000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311100</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98312000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:Region>anyw-cou</cbc:Region>
          <cac:Country>
            <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
          </cac:Country>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:StartDate>2026-05-31Z</cbc:StartDate>
        <cbc:EndDate>2032-05-31Z</cbc:EndDate>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0004</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-trade</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers are registered in a company register or a trade register in the member state in which the tenderer is established. As described in annex XI of directive 2014/24/EU; suppliers from certain member states may have to fulfil other requirements in the mentioned annex.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-to-gen</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The tenderer ́s ("total") annual turnover for the number of financial years requested in the tender notice or in the procurement documents is as follows:
Minimum qualification requirements</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Regarding any other economic and financial requirements that have been stated in the notice or in the procurement documents, the tenderer declares that:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient economic and financial solidity to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Sufficient economic and financial solidity means that the tenderer shall fulfil the following requirements:
• Tenderers are required to have a turnover equivalent to the estimated annual value of the lot(s) that a tender is submitted for.
• Tenderers are required to be "credit worthy without security".

Documentation requirement:
The Contracting Authority will evaluate the Tenderer's fulfilment of the qualification requirements in the following manner:  
• The last submitted Annual Financial Statements with notes including the auditor's statement, possibly income statement and/or the balance sheet for the last year, if it is more than six months since the last annual accounts.
• Tenderers shall, through documentation from a certified credit rating company, document that the tenderer is 'credit worthy without collateral'. The contracting authority reserves the right to verify documentation by carrying out a separate credit rating. The credit rating must not be older than 6 months from the submission date of the tender offer.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-ref-services</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Only for services: In the reference period, the tenderer has carried out the following important goods deliveries of the requested type, or the following important services of the requested type. The contracting authority can require up to three years experience and allow experience from the previous three years to be taken into consideration.
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have experience from deliveries to the health sector.

Documentation requirement:
Description of the tenderer ́s up to 3 relevant deliveries to the health sector. The description shall include a statement of the contract ́s value, date and recipient (name, telephone number and e-mail address).</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-facil-tools</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers can use the following tools, material and technical equipment to carry out the contract:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient ability and capacity to be able to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Tenderers are required to have laundry(s) with sufficient capacity to serve the tenderer/sub-contract(s) that a tender is submitted for. 

If the tenderer is planning to use the existing laundry(s), the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at the existing facilities. 

If the tenderer plans to construct a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at planned facilities, as well as a schedule (including realistic progress from the planning phase to completion).

The requirement also applies for a stand-by laundry system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall document the following:
Description of the technical facilities, including the laundry size and extent. (Max. 1 A4 page).

If a tenderer shall establish a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, a description of the technical facilities shall be presented at the start of the agreement, as outlined above, as well as a copy of the rent or purchase contract connected to the local(s). If the tenderer has not entered into a hire or procurement contract, a copy of the necessary building permits or drawings with information related to geographical locations will also be accepted. In addition a realistic progress plan shall be delivered that outlines progress from planning to completion.

If documentation is submitted for the existing facilities, this will form the basis of the assessment of whether the qualification requirement is fulfilled. 

If documentation is submitted for planned facilities, the description of the technical facilities at the start of the agreement will apply.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-qu-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Can tenderers submit certificates issued by independent bodies that document that the tenderer fulfils the stated quality assurance standards, including universal design requirements?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a certified quality assurance system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s quality system is certified. The certificate shall show that the quality system is based on relevant European standard series, for example ISO 9001. The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. 

The contracting authority will accept other documentation for an equivalent quality system if the tenderer cannot obtain such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures correspond to the requested quality standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-env-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer able to submit certificates issued by independent bodies as documentation that the tenderer fulfils the stated environmental management systems or standards?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a third-party certified environmental management system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s environmental management system is certified. The certificate shall show that the environmental management system is based on relevant European or international standards, for example ISO14001, EMAS, Miljøfyrtårn . 

The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. The contracting authority will accept other documentation for equivalent environmental management measures if the tenderer does not have the possibility to receive such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures are equivalent to the requested environmental management systems or standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:FundingProgramCode listName="eu-funded">no-eu-funds</cbc:FundingProgramCode>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <ext:UBLExtensions>
          <ext:UBLExtension>
            <ext:ExtensionContent>
              <efext:EformsExtension>
                <efac:OfficialLanguages>
                  <cac:Language>
                    <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
                  </cac:Language>
                </efac:OfficialLanguages>
              </efext:EformsExtension>
            </ext:ExtensionContent>
          </ext:UBLExtension>
        </ext:UBLExtensions>
        <cbc:ID>258093032</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="esignature-submission">true</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:EndpointID>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="MONTH">6</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">After the award, a 10 day waiting period is set before it is signed.</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealInformationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealInformationParty>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
        <cac:MediationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:MediationParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
      <cac:PostAwardProcess>
        <cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>
        <cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>
      </cac:PostAwardProcess>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-06-30+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
      <cac:OpenTenderEvent>
        <cbc:OccurrenceDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceDate>
        <cbc:OccurrenceTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceTime>
      </cac:OpenTenderEvent>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:FrameworkAgreement>
        <cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>100</cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>
        
        <cbc:Justification languageID="ENG">A long duration, and consequently depreciation time, gives laundry suppliers who are not currently able to invest in order to get a contract. The agreement period of 6 years + 2 years will increase the competition.</cbc:Justification>
      </cac:FrameworkAgreement>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">fa-wo-rc</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025/51036</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">DK4 Nordlandssykehuset HF</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Hire and laundry of work clothes, patient clothes and flat textiles for NordlandSsykehuset HF.</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98310000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311100</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98312000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:Region>anyw-cou</cbc:Region>
          <cac:Country>
            <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
          </cac:Country>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:StartDate>2026-05-31Z</cbc:StartDate>
        <cbc:EndDate>2032-05-31Z</cbc:EndDate>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0005</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-trade</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers are registered in a company register or a trade register in the member state in which the tenderer is established. As described in annex XI of directive 2014/24/EU; suppliers from certain member states may have to fulfil other requirements in the mentioned annex.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-to-gen</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The tenderer ́s ("total") annual turnover for the number of financial years requested in the tender notice or in the procurement documents is as follows:
Minimum qualification requirements</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Regarding any other economic and financial requirements that have been stated in the notice or in the procurement documents, the tenderer declares that:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient economic and financial solidity to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Sufficient economic and financial solidity means that the tenderer shall fulfil the following requirements:
• Tenderers are required to have a turnover equivalent to the estimated annual value of the lot(s) that a tender is submitted for.
• Tenderers are required to be "credit worthy without security".

Documentation requirement:
The Contracting Authority will evaluate the Tenderer's fulfilment of the qualification requirements in the following manner:  
• The last submitted Annual Financial Statements with notes including the auditor's statement, possibly income statement and/or the balance sheet for the last year, if it is more than six months since the last annual accounts.
• Tenderers shall, through documentation from a certified credit rating company, document that the tenderer is 'credit worthy without collateral'. The contracting authority reserves the right to verify documentation by carrying out a separate credit rating. The credit rating must not be older than 6 months from the submission date of the tender offer.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-ref-services</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Only for services: In the reference period, the tenderer has carried out the following important goods deliveries of the requested type, or the following important services of the requested type. The contracting authority can require up to three years experience and allow experience from the previous three years to be taken into consideration.
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have experience from deliveries to the health sector.

Documentation requirement:
Description of the tenderer ́s up to 3 relevant deliveries to the health sector. The description shall include a statement of the contract ́s value, date and recipient (name, telephone number and e-mail address).</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-facil-tools</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers can use the following tools, material and technical equipment to carry out the contract:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient ability and capacity to be able to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Tenderers are required to have laundry(s) with sufficient capacity to serve the tenderer/sub-contract(s) that a tender is submitted for. 

If the tenderer is planning to use the existing laundry(s), the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at the existing facilities. 

If the tenderer plans to construct a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at planned facilities, as well as a schedule (including realistic progress from the planning phase to completion).

The requirement also applies for a stand-by laundry system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall document the following:
Description of the technical facilities, including the laundry size and extent. (Max. 1 A4 page).

If a tenderer shall establish a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, a description of the technical facilities shall be presented at the start of the agreement, as outlined above, as well as a copy of the rent or purchase contract connected to the local(s). If the tenderer has not entered into a hire or procurement contract, a copy of the necessary building permits or drawings with information related to geographical locations will also be accepted. In addition a realistic progress plan shall be delivered that outlines progress from planning to completion.

If documentation is submitted for the existing facilities, this will form the basis of the assessment of whether the qualification requirement is fulfilled. 

If documentation is submitted for planned facilities, the description of the technical facilities at the start of the agreement will apply.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-qu-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Can tenderers submit certificates issued by independent bodies that document that the tenderer fulfils the stated quality assurance standards, including universal design requirements?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a certified quality assurance system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s quality system is certified. The certificate shall show that the quality system is based on relevant European standard series, for example ISO 9001. The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. 

The contracting authority will accept other documentation for an equivalent quality system if the tenderer cannot obtain such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures correspond to the requested quality standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-env-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer able to submit certificates issued by independent bodies as documentation that the tenderer fulfils the stated environmental management systems or standards?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a third-party certified environmental management system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s environmental management system is certified. The certificate shall show that the environmental management system is based on relevant European or international standards, for example ISO14001, EMAS, Miljøfyrtårn . 

The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. The contracting authority will accept other documentation for equivalent environmental management measures if the tenderer does not have the possibility to receive such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures are equivalent to the requested environmental management systems or standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:FundingProgramCode listName="eu-funded">no-eu-funds</cbc:FundingProgramCode>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <ext:UBLExtensions>
          <ext:UBLExtension>
            <ext:ExtensionContent>
              <efext:EformsExtension>
                <efac:OfficialLanguages>
                  <cac:Language>
                    <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
                  </cac:Language>
                </efac:OfficialLanguages>
              </efext:EformsExtension>
            </ext:ExtensionContent>
          </ext:UBLExtension>
        </ext:UBLExtensions>
        <cbc:ID>258093093</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="esignature-submission">true</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:EndpointID>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="MONTH">6</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">After the award, 10 days from the waiting period must be set before it is signed.</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealInformationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealInformationParty>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
        <cac:MediationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:MediationParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
      <cac:PostAwardProcess>
        <cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>
        <cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>
      </cac:PostAwardProcess>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-06-30+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
      <cac:OpenTenderEvent>
        <cbc:OccurrenceDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceDate>
        <cbc:OccurrenceTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceTime>
      </cac:OpenTenderEvent>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:FrameworkAgreement>
        <cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>100</cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>
        
        <cbc:Justification languageID="ENG">A long duration and, thus, long depreciation period, gives laundry suppliers who are not currently able to invest in order to be relevant tenderers. The agreement period of 6 years + 2 years will increase the competition.</cbc:Justification>
      </cac:FrameworkAgreement>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">fa-wo-rc</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025/51037</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">DK5 Helgelandssykehuset HF</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Hire and laundry of work clothes, patient clothes and flat textiles for Helgelandssykehuset HF.</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98310000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311100</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98312000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:Region>anyw-cou</cbc:Region>
          <cac:Country>
            <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
          </cac:Country>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:StartDate>2026-05-31Z</cbc:StartDate>
        <cbc:EndDate>2032-05-31Z</cbc:EndDate>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0006</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-trade</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers are registered in a company register or a trade register in the member state in which the tenderer is established. As described in annex XI of directive 2014/24/EU; suppliers from certain member states may have to fulfil other requirements in the mentioned annex.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-to-gen</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The tenderer ́s ("total") annual turnover for the number of financial years requested in the tender notice or in the procurement documents is as follows:
Minimum qualification requirements</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Regarding any other economic and financial requirements that have been stated in the notice or in the procurement documents, the tenderer declares that:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient economic and financial solidity to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Sufficient economic and financial solidity means that the tenderer shall fulfil the following requirements:
• Tenderers are required to have a turnover equivalent to the estimated annual value of the lot(s) that a tender is submitted for.
• Tenderers are required to be "credit worthy without security".

Documentation requirement:
The Contracting Authority will evaluate the Tenderer's fulfilment of the qualification requirements in the following manner:  
• The last submitted Annual Financial Statements with notes including the auditor's statement, possibly income statement and/or the balance sheet for the last year, if it is more than six months since the last annual accounts.
• Tenderers shall, through documentation from a certified credit rating company, document that the tenderer is 'credit worthy without collateral'. The contracting authority reserves the right to verify documentation by carrying out a separate credit rating. The credit rating must not be older than 6 months from the submission date of the tender offer.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-ref-services</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Only for services: In the reference period, the tenderer has carried out the following important goods deliveries of the requested type, or the following important services of the requested type. The contracting authority can require up to three years experience and allow experience from the previous three years to be taken into consideration.
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have experience from deliveries to the health sector.

Documentation requirement:
Description of the tenderer ́s up to 3 relevant deliveries to the health sector. The description shall include a statement of the contract ́s value, date and recipient (name, telephone number and e-mail address).</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-facil-tools</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers can use the following tools, material and technical equipment to carry out the contract:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient ability and capacity to be able to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Tenderers are required to have laundry(s) with sufficient capacity to serve the tenderer/sub-contract(s) that a tender is submitted for. 

If the tenderer is planning to use the existing laundry(s), the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at the existing facilities. 

If the tenderer plans to construct a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at planned facilities, as well as a schedule (including realistic progress from the planning phase to completion).

The requirement also applies for a stand-by laundry system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall document the following:
Description of the technical facilities, including the laundry size and extent. (Max. 1 A4 page).

If a tenderer shall establish a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, a description of the technical facilities shall be presented at the start of the agreement, as outlined above, as well as a copy of the rent or purchase contract connected to the local(s). If the tenderer has not entered into a hire or procurement contract, a copy of the necessary building permits or drawings with information related to geographical locations will also be accepted. In addition a realistic progress plan shall be delivered that outlines progress from planning to completion.

If documentation is submitted for the existing facilities, this will form the basis of the assessment of whether the qualification requirement is fulfilled. 

If documentation is submitted for planned facilities, the description of the technical facilities at the start of the agreement will apply.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-qu-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Can tenderers submit certificates issued by independent bodies that document that the tenderer fulfils the stated quality assurance standards, including universal design requirements?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a certified quality assurance system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s quality system is certified. The certificate shall show that the quality system is based on relevant European standard series, for example ISO 9001. The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. 

The contracting authority will accept other documentation for an equivalent quality system if the tenderer cannot obtain such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures correspond to the requested quality standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-env-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer able to submit certificates issued by independent bodies as documentation that the tenderer fulfils the stated environmental management systems or standards?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a third-party certified environmental management system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s environmental management system is certified. The certificate shall show that the environmental management system is based on relevant European or international standards, for example ISO14001, EMAS, Miljøfyrtårn . 

The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. The contracting authority will accept other documentation for equivalent environmental management measures if the tenderer does not have the possibility to receive such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures are equivalent to the requested environmental management systems or standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:FundingProgramCode listName="eu-funded">no-eu-funds</cbc:FundingProgramCode>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <ext:UBLExtensions>
          <ext:UBLExtension>
            <ext:ExtensionContent>
              <efext:EformsExtension>
                <efac:OfficialLanguages>
                  <cac:Language>
                    <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
                  </cac:Language>
                </efac:OfficialLanguages>
              </efext:EformsExtension>
            </ext:ExtensionContent>
          </ext:UBLExtension>
        </ext:UBLExtensions>
        <cbc:ID>258093350</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="esignature-submission">true</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:EndpointID>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="MONTH">6</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">After the award, 10 days waiting period is set before signing</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealInformationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealInformationParty>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
        <cac:MediationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:MediationParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
      <cac:PostAwardProcess>
        <cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>
        <cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>
      </cac:PostAwardProcess>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-06-30+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
      <cac:OpenTenderEvent>
        <cbc:OccurrenceDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceDate>
        <cbc:OccurrenceTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceTime>
      </cac:OpenTenderEvent>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:FrameworkAgreement>
        <cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>100</cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>
        
        <cbc:Justification languageID="ENG">A long duration and, thus, long depreciation period, gives laundry suppliers who are not currently able to invest in order to be relevant tenderers. The agreement period of 6 years + 2 years will increase the competition.</cbc:Justification>
      </cac:FrameworkAgreement>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">fa-wo-rc</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025/51039</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">DK7 Helse Møre og Romsdal HF Sør</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Hire and laundry of work clothes, patient clothes and flat textiles for Helse Møre og Romsdal HF Sør.</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98310000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311100</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98312000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:Region>anyw-cou</cbc:Region>
          <cac:Country>
            <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
          </cac:Country>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:StartDate>2026-05-31Z</cbc:StartDate>
        <cbc:EndDate>2032-05-31Z</cbc:EndDate>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0007</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-trade</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers are registered in a company register or a trade register in the member state in which the tenderer is established. As described in annex XI of directive 2014/24/EU; suppliers from certain member states may have to fulfil other requirements in the mentioned annex.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-to-gen</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The tenderer ́s ("total") annual turnover for the number of financial years requested in the tender notice or in the procurement documents is as follows:
Minimum qualification requirements</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Regarding any other economic and financial requirements that have been stated in the notice or in the procurement documents, the tenderer declares that:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient economic and financial solidity to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Sufficient economic and financial solidity means that the tenderer shall fulfil the following requirements:
• Tenderers are required to have a turnover equivalent to the estimated annual value of the lot(s) that a tender is submitted for.
• Tenderers are required to be "credit worthy without security".

Documentation requirement:
The Contracting Authority will evaluate the Tenderer's fulfilment of the qualification requirements in the following manner:  
• The last submitted Annual Financial Statements with notes including the auditor's statement, possibly income statement and/or the balance sheet for the last year, if it is more than six months since the last annual accounts.
• Tenderers shall, through documentation from a certified credit rating company, document that the tenderer is 'credit worthy without collateral'. The contracting authority reserves the right to verify documentation by carrying out a separate credit rating. The credit rating must not be older than 6 months from the submission date of the tender offer.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-ref-services</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Only for services: In the reference period, the tenderer has carried out the following important goods deliveries of the requested type, or the following important services of the requested type. The contracting authority can require up to three years experience and allow experience from the previous three years to be taken into consideration.
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have experience from deliveries to the health sector.

Documentation requirement:
Description of the tenderer ́s up to 3 relevant deliveries to the health sector. The description shall include a statement of the contract ́s value, date and recipient (name, telephone number and e-mail address).</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-facil-tools</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers can use the following tools, material and technical equipment to carry out the contract:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient ability and capacity to be able to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Tenderers are required to have laundry(s) with sufficient capacity to serve the tenderer/sub-contract(s) that a tender is submitted for. 

If the tenderer is planning to use the existing laundry(s), the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at the existing facilities. 

If the tenderer plans to construct a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at planned facilities, as well as a schedule (including realistic progress from the planning phase to completion).

The requirement also applies for a stand-by laundry system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall document the following:
Description of the technical facilities, including the laundry size and extent. (Max. 1 A4 page).

If a tenderer shall establish a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, a description of the technical facilities shall be presented at the start of the agreement, as outlined above, as well as a copy of the rent or purchase contract connected to the local(s). If the tenderer has not entered into a hire or procurement contract, a copy of the necessary building permits or drawings with information related to geographical locations will also be accepted. In addition a realistic progress plan shall be delivered that outlines progress from planning to completion.

If documentation is submitted for the existing facilities, this will form the basis of the assessment of whether the qualification requirement is fulfilled. 

If documentation is submitted for planned facilities, the description of the technical facilities at the start of the agreement will apply.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-qu-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Can tenderers submit certificates issued by independent bodies that document that the tenderer fulfils the stated quality assurance standards, including universal design requirements?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a certified quality assurance system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s quality system is certified. The certificate shall show that the quality system is based on relevant European standard series, for example ISO 9001. The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. 

The contracting authority will accept other documentation for an equivalent quality system if the tenderer cannot obtain such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures correspond to the requested quality standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-env-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer able to submit certificates issued by independent bodies as documentation that the tenderer fulfils the stated environmental management systems or standards?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a third-party certified environmental management system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s environmental management system is certified. The certificate shall show that the environmental management system is based on relevant European or international standards, for example ISO14001, EMAS, Miljøfyrtårn . 

The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. The contracting authority will accept other documentation for equivalent environmental management measures if the tenderer does not have the possibility to receive such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures are equivalent to the requested environmental management systems or standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:FundingProgramCode listName="eu-funded">no-eu-funds</cbc:FundingProgramCode>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <ext:UBLExtensions>
          <ext:UBLExtension>
            <ext:ExtensionContent>
              <efext:EformsExtension>
                <efac:OfficialLanguages>
                  <cac:Language>
                    <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
                  </cac:Language>
                </efac:OfficialLanguages>
              </efext:EformsExtension>
            </ext:ExtensionContent>
          </ext:UBLExtension>
        </ext:UBLExtensions>
        <cbc:ID>258093399</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="esignature-submission">true</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:EndpointID>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="MONTH">6</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The waiting period is 10 days after the contract has been awarded.</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealInformationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealInformationParty>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
        <cac:MediationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:MediationParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
      <cac:PostAwardProcess>
        <cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>
        <cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>
      </cac:PostAwardProcess>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-06-30+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
      <cac:OpenTenderEvent>
        <cbc:OccurrenceDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceDate>
        <cbc:OccurrenceTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceTime>
      </cac:OpenTenderEvent>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:FrameworkAgreement>
        <cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>100</cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>
        
        <cbc:Justification languageID="ENG">A long duration and, thus, long depreciation period, gives laundry suppliers who are not currently able to invest in order to be relevant tenderers. The agreement period of 6 years + 2 years will increase the competition.</cbc:Justification>
      </cac:FrameworkAgreement>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">fa-wo-rc</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025/51038</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">DK6 Helse Møre og Romsdal HF Nord</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Hire and laundry of work clothes, patient clothes and flat textiles for Helse Møre og Romsdal HF Nord.</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98310000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311100</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98312000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:Region>anyw-cou</cbc:Region>
          <cac:Country>
            <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
          </cac:Country>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:StartDate>2026-05-31Z</cbc:StartDate>
        <cbc:EndDate>2032-05-31Z</cbc:EndDate>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0008</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-trade</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers are registered in a company register or a trade register in the member state in which the tenderer is established. As described in annex XI of directive 2014/24/EU; suppliers from certain member states may have to fulfil other requirements in the mentioned annex.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-to-gen</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The tenderer ́s ("total") annual turnover for the number of financial years requested in the tender notice or in the procurement documents is as follows:
Minimum qualification requirements</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Regarding any other economic and financial requirements that have been stated in the notice or in the procurement documents, the tenderer declares that:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient economic and financial solidity to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Sufficient economic and financial solidity means that the tenderer shall fulfil the following requirements:
• Tenderers are required to have a turnover equivalent to the estimated annual value of the lot(s) that a tender is submitted for.
• Tenderers are required to be "credit worthy without security".

Documentation requirement:
The Contracting Authority will evaluate the Tenderer's fulfilment of the qualification requirements in the following manner:  
• The last submitted Annual Financial Statements with notes including the auditor's statement, possibly income statement and/or the balance sheet for the last year, if it is more than six months since the last annual accounts.
• Tenderers shall, through documentation from a certified credit rating company, document that the tenderer is 'credit worthy without collateral'. The contracting authority reserves the right to verify documentation by carrying out a separate credit rating. The credit rating must not be older than 6 months from the submission date of the tender offer.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-ref-services</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Only for services: In the reference period, the tenderer has carried out the following important goods deliveries of the requested type, or the following important services of the requested type. The contracting authority can require up to three years experience and allow experience from the previous three years to be taken into consideration.
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have experience from deliveries to the health sector.

Documentation requirement:
Description of the tenderer ́s up to 3 relevant deliveries to the health sector. The description shall include a statement of the contract ́s value, date and recipient (name, telephone number and e-mail address).</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-facil-tools</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers can use the following tools, material and technical equipment to carry out the contract:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient ability and capacity to be able to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Tenderers are required to have laundry(s) with sufficient capacity to serve the tenderer/sub-contract(s) that a tender is submitted for. 

If the tenderer is planning to use the existing laundry(s), the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at the existing facilities. 

If the tenderer plans to construct a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at planned facilities, as well as a schedule (including realistic progress from the planning phase to completion).

The requirement also applies for a stand-by laundry system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall document the following:
Description of the technical facilities, including the laundry size and extent. (Max. 1 A4 page).

If a tenderer shall establish a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, a description of the technical facilities shall be presented at the start of the agreement, as outlined above, as well as a copy of the rent or purchase contract connected to the local(s). If the tenderer has not entered into a hire or procurement contract, a copy of the necessary building permits or drawings with information related to geographical locations will also be accepted. In addition a realistic progress plan shall be delivered that outlines progress from planning to completion.

If documentation is submitted for the existing facilities, this will form the basis of the assessment of whether the qualification requirement is fulfilled. 

If documentation is submitted for planned facilities, the description of the technical facilities at the start of the agreement will apply.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-qu-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Can tenderers submit certificates issued by independent bodies that document that the tenderer fulfils the stated quality assurance standards, including universal design requirements?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a certified quality assurance system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s quality system is certified. The certificate shall show that the quality system is based on relevant European standard series, for example ISO 9001. The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. 

The contracting authority will accept other documentation for an equivalent quality system if the tenderer cannot obtain such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures correspond to the requested quality standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-env-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer able to submit certificates issued by independent bodies as documentation that the tenderer fulfils the stated environmental management systems or standards?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a third-party certified environmental management system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s environmental management system is certified. The certificate shall show that the environmental management system is based on relevant European or international standards, for example ISO14001, EMAS, Miljøfyrtårn . 

The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. The contracting authority will accept other documentation for equivalent environmental management measures if the tenderer does not have the possibility to receive such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures are equivalent to the requested environmental management systems or standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:FundingProgramCode listName="eu-funded">no-eu-funds</cbc:FundingProgramCode>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <ext:UBLExtensions>
          <ext:UBLExtension>
            <ext:ExtensionContent>
              <efext:EformsExtension>
                <efac:OfficialLanguages>
                  <cac:Language>
                    <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
                  </cac:Language>
                </efac:OfficialLanguages>
              </efext:EformsExtension>
            </ext:ExtensionContent>
          </ext:UBLExtension>
        </ext:UBLExtensions>
        <cbc:ID>258093439</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="esignature-submission">true</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:EndpointID>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="MONTH">6</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The waiting period is 10 days after the contract has been awarded.</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealInformationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealInformationParty>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
        <cac:MediationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:MediationParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
      <cac:PostAwardProcess>
        <cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>
        <cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>
      </cac:PostAwardProcess>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-06-30+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
      <cac:OpenTenderEvent>
        <cbc:OccurrenceDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceDate>
        <cbc:OccurrenceTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceTime>
      </cac:OpenTenderEvent>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:FrameworkAgreement>
        <cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>100</cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>
        
        <cbc:Justification languageID="ENG">A long duration and, thus, long depreciation period, gives laundry suppliers who are not currently able to invest in order to be relevant tenderers. The agreement period of 6 years + 2 years will increase the competition.</cbc:Justification>
      </cac:FrameworkAgreement>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">fa-wo-rc</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025/51040</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">DK8 Helse Fonna HF Haugesund</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Hire and laundry of work clothes, patient clothes and flat textiles for Helse Fonna HF Haugesund.</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98310000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311100</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98312000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:Region>anyw-cou</cbc:Region>
          <cac:Country>
            <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
          </cac:Country>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:StartDate>2026-11-30Z</cbc:StartDate>
        <cbc:EndDate>2032-11-30Z</cbc:EndDate>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0009</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-trade</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers are registered in a company register or a trade register in the member state in which the tenderer is established. As described in annex XI of directive 2014/24/EU; suppliers from certain member states may have to fulfil other requirements in the mentioned annex.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-to-gen</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The tenderer ́s ("total") annual turnover for the number of financial years requested in the tender notice or in the procurement documents is as follows:
Minimum qualification requirements</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Regarding any other economic and financial requirements that have been stated in the notice or in the procurement documents, the tenderer declares that:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient economic and financial solidity to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Sufficient economic and financial solidity means that the tenderer shall fulfil the following requirements:
• Tenderers are required to have a turnover equivalent to the estimated annual value of the lot(s) that a tender is submitted for.
• Tenderers are required to be "credit worthy without security".

Documentation requirement:
The Contracting Authority will evaluate the Tenderer's fulfilment of the qualification requirements in the following manner:  
• The last submitted Annual Financial Statements with notes including the auditor's statement, possibly income statement and/or the balance sheet for the last year, if it is more than six months since the last annual accounts.
• Tenderers shall, through documentation from a certified credit rating company, document that the tenderer is 'credit worthy without collateral'. The contracting authority reserves the right to verify documentation by carrying out a separate credit rating. The credit rating must not be older than 6 months from the submission date of the tender offer.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-ref-services</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Only for services: In the reference period, the tenderer has carried out the following important goods deliveries of the requested type, or the following important services of the requested type. The contracting authority can require up to three years experience and allow experience from the previous three years to be taken into consideration.
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have experience from deliveries to the health sector.

Documentation requirement:
Description of the tenderer ́s up to 3 relevant deliveries to the health sector. The description shall include a statement of the contract ́s value, date and recipient (name, telephone number and e-mail address).</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-facil-tools</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers can use the following tools, material and technical equipment to carry out the contract:
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have sufficient ability and capacity to be able to fulfil the contractual obligations.

Tenderers are required to have laundry(s) with sufficient capacity to serve the tenderer/sub-contract(s) that a tender is submitted for. 

If the tenderer is planning to use the existing laundry(s), the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at the existing facilities. 

If the tenderer plans to construct a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, the contracting authority will emphasise production capacity at planned facilities, as well as a schedule (including realistic progress from the planning phase to completion).

The requirement also applies for a stand-by laundry system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall document the following:
Description of the technical facilities, including the laundry size and extent. (Max. 1 A4 page).

If a tenderer shall establish a new laundry, or expand the existing laundry, a description of the technical facilities shall be presented at the start of the agreement, as outlined above, as well as a copy of the rent or purchase contract connected to the local(s). If the tenderer has not entered into a hire or procurement contract, a copy of the necessary building permits or drawings with information related to geographical locations will also be accepted. In addition a realistic progress plan shall be delivered that outlines progress from planning to completion.

If documentation is submitted for the existing facilities, this will form the basis of the assessment of whether the qualification requirement is fulfilled. 

If documentation is submitted for planned facilities, the description of the technical facilities at the start of the agreement will apply.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-qu-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Can tenderers submit certificates issued by independent bodies that document that the tenderer fulfils the stated quality assurance standards, including universal design requirements?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a certified quality assurance system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s quality system is certified. The certificate shall show that the quality system is based on relevant European standard series, for example ISO 9001. The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. 

The contracting authority will accept other documentation for an equivalent quality system if the tenderer cannot obtain such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures correspond to the requested quality standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-env-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer able to submit certificates issued by independent bodies as documentation that the tenderer fulfils the stated environmental management systems or standards?
Minimum qualification requirements
Qualification requirement:
Tenderers shall have a third-party certified environmental management system.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall present a certificate from an independent body that confirms that the tenderer ́s environmental management system is certified. The certificate shall show that the environmental management system is based on relevant European or international standards, for example ISO14001, EMAS, Miljøfyrtårn . 

The contracting authority will also accept certificates issued by bodies in other EEA countries. The contracting authority will accept other documentation for equivalent environmental management measures if the tenderer does not have the possibility to receive such certificates by the deadline, and this is not due to the tenderer himself. It is a prerequisite that the tenderer documents that these measures are equivalent to the requested environmental management systems or standards.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:FundingProgramCode listName="eu-funded">no-eu-funds</cbc:FundingProgramCode>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <ext:UBLExtensions>
          <ext:UBLExtension>
            <ext:ExtensionContent>
              <efext:EformsExtension>
                <efac:OfficialLanguages>
                  <cac:Language>
                    <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
                  </cac:Language>
                </efac:OfficialLanguages>
              </efext:EformsExtension>
            </ext:ExtensionContent>
          </ext:UBLExtension>
        </ext:UBLExtensions>
        <cbc:ID>258093470</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="esignature-submission">true</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://permalink.mercell.com/258081276.aspx</cbc:EndpointID>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="MONTH">6</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">After the award, 10 days waiting period is set before signing</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealInformationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealInformationParty>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
        <cac:MediationParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:MediationParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
      <cac:PostAwardProcess>
        <cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>
        <cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>
      </cac:PostAwardProcess>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-06-30+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
      <cac:OpenTenderEvent>
        <cbc:OccurrenceDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceDate>
        <cbc:OccurrenceTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceTime>
      </cac:OpenTenderEvent>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:FrameworkAgreement>
        <cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>100</cbc:MaximumOperatorQuantity>
        
        <cbc:Justification languageID="ENG">A long duration and, thus, long depreciation period, gives laundry suppliers who are not currently able to invest in order to be relevant tenderers. The agreement period of 6 years + 2 years will increase the competition.</cbc:Justification>
      </cac:FrameworkAgreement>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">fa-wo-rc</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025/51041</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">DK9 Helse Fonna HF Valen, Odda and Stord</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Hire and laundry of work clothes, patient clothes and flat textiles for Helse Fonna HF Valen, Odda and Stord.</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98310000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311100</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98311200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">98312000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:Region>anyw-cou</cbc:Region>
          <cac:Country>
            <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
          </cac:Country>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:StartDate>2026-11-30Z</cbc:StartDate>
        <cbc:EndDate>2032-11-30Z</cbc:EndDate>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
</ContractNotice>