<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><ContractNotice xmlns="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:ContractNotice-2" xmlns:cac="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonAggregateComponents-2" xmlns:cbc="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonBasicComponents-2" xmlns:efac="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extension-aggregate-components/1" xmlns:efbc="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extension-basic-components/1" xmlns:efext="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extensions/1" xmlns:ext="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonExtensionComponents-2">
  <ext:UBLExtensions>
    <ext:UBLExtension>
      <ext:ExtensionContent>
        <efext:EformsExtension>
          <efbc:TransmissionDate>2025-06-05+00:00</efbc:TransmissionDate>
          <efbc:TransmissionTime>09:00:08+00:00</efbc:TransmissionTime>
          <efac:NoticeSubType>
            <cbc:SubTypeCode listName="notice-subtype">16</cbc:SubTypeCode>
          </efac:NoticeSubType>
          <efac:Organizations>
            <efac:Organization>
              <efac:Company>
                <cbc:WebsiteURI>http://www.nve.no</cbc:WebsiteURI>
                <cac:PartyIdentification>
                  <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
                </cac:PartyIdentification>
                
                <cac:PartyName>
                  <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Norges vassdrags- og energidirektorat (NVE)</cbc:Name>
                </cac:PartyName>
                <cac:PostalAddress>
                  <cbc:StreetName>Middelthunsgate 29</cbc:StreetName>
                  <cbc:CityName>OSLO</cbc:CityName>
                  <cbc:PostalZone>0368</cbc:PostalZone>
                  <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO081</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
                  <cac:Country>
                    <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
                  </cac:Country>
                </cac:PostalAddress>
                <cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                  <cbc:CompanyID schemeID="002">970205039</cbc:CompanyID>
                </cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                <cac:Contact>
                  <cbc:Name>Cecilie Thiis</cbc:Name>
                  <cbc:Telephone>+47 22959595</cbc:Telephone>
                  <cbc:ElectronicMail>cecilie.thiis@inventura.no</cbc:ElectronicMail>
                </cac:Contact>
              </efac:Company>
            </efac:Organization>
            <efac:Organization>
              <efac:Company>
                <cac:PartyIdentification>
                  <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
                </cac:PartyIdentification>
                
                <cac:PartyName>
                  <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Oslo Tingrett</cbc:Name>
                </cac:PartyName>
                <cac:PostalAddress>
                  <cbc:CityName>Oslo</cbc:CityName>
                  <cbc:PostalZone>0125</cbc:PostalZone>
                  <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO081</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
                  <cac:Country>
                    <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
                  </cac:Country>
                </cac:PostalAddress>
                <cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                  <cbc:CompanyID schemeID="002">926725939</cbc:CompanyID>
                </cac:PartyLegalEntity>
              </efac:Company>
            </efac:Organization>
          </efac:Organizations>
        <efac:Publication><efbc:NoticePublicationID schemeName="ojs-notice-id">00366238-2025</efbc:NoticePublicationID><efbc:GazetteID schemeName="ojs-id">108/2025</efbc:GazetteID><efbc:PublicationDate>2025-06-06+02:00</efbc:PublicationDate></efac:Publication></efext:EformsExtension>
      </ext:ExtensionContent>
    </ext:UBLExtension>
  </ext:UBLExtensions>
  <cbc:UBLVersionID>2.3</cbc:UBLVersionID>
  <cbc:CustomizationID>eforms-sdk-1.13</cbc:CustomizationID>
  <cbc:ID schemeName="notice-id">4a7f0111-3c94-4966-9a2a-99bd99d52170</cbc:ID>
  <cbc:ContractFolderID>1df1b42f-2f36-4c4f-a4c8-b5215f7ab2e4</cbc:ContractFolderID>
  <cbc:IssueDate>2025-06-05+00:00</cbc:IssueDate>
  <cbc:IssueTime>08:50:24+00:00</cbc:IssueTime>
  <cbc:VersionID>01</cbc:VersionID>
  <cbc:RegulatoryDomain>32014L0024</cbc:RegulatoryDomain>
  <cbc:NoticeTypeCode listName="competition">cn-standard</cbc:NoticeTypeCode>
  <cbc:NoticeLanguageCode>ENG</cbc:NoticeLanguageCode>
  
  <cac:ContractingParty>
    <cac:ContractingPartyType>
      <cbc:PartyTypeCode listName="buyer-legal-type">cga</cbc:PartyTypeCode>
    </cac:ContractingPartyType>
    <cac:ContractingActivity>
      <cbc:ActivityTypeCode listName="authority-activity">gen-pub</cbc:ActivityTypeCode>
    </cac:ContractingActivity>
    <cac:Party>
      <cac:PartyIdentification>
        <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
      </cac:PartyIdentification>
    </cac:Party>
  </cac:ContractingParty>
  <cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:ProcurementLegislationDocumentReference>
      <cbc:ID>Anskaffelsesforskriften</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:DocumentDescription languageID="ENG">This procurement will be carried out in accordance with the Act from 17 June 2016 no. 73 on public procurements (LOA) and the regulation 12 August 2016 no. 974 on public procurements (FOA). 

The procurement will be carried out as an open tender contest in accordance with PPR parts I and III. This procedure gives all interested tenderers the possibility to submit tenders for the competition.</cbc:DocumentDescription>
    </cac:ProcurementLegislationDocumentReference>
    <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-corrpt</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a enforceable verdict has been convicted of corruption by a verdict handed down not more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Corruption as defined in Article 3 of the Convention on Combating Corruption, Involving European Communities or European Union Member States (EUT C 195 of 25.6.1997, s. 1), and in Article 2, point 1, in the Council ́s framework decision 2003/568/RIA of 22 July 2003 on combating corruption in the private sector (EUT L 192 of 31.7.2003,  p. 54). This rejection reason also includes corruption as defined in national law for the contracting authority or supplier.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-fraud</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, at the time a legally convicted of fraud has been convicted of fraud by a verdict handed down not more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Fraud included in Article 1 of the Convention on protection of the Financial Interests of the European Communities (EFT C 316 of 27.11.1995, p. 48).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-laund</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of money laundering or financing terrorism by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Money laundering or financing terrorism As defined in Article 1 of the European Parliament and Council Directive 2005/60/EF of 26 October 2005 on preventive measures against the use of the financial system for money laundering and financing terrorism (EUT L 309 of 25.11.2005, p. 15).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-part</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, at the time a legally convicted verdict of participation in a criminal organisation by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Participation in a criminal organisation as defined in Article 2 of the Council ́s framework decision 2008/841/RIA of 24 October 2008 on control of organised crime (EUT L 300 of 11.11.2008, p. 42)</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-terror</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body, or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of acts of terrorism or criminal acts connected to terrorist activities by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Acts of terrorism or criminal acts relating to terrorist activity as defined in Article 1 and 3 of the Council ́s framework decision 2002/475/RIA of 13 June 2002 on combating terrorism (EFT L 164, af 22.6.2002, p. 3). This rejection reason also includes incitement to, participation or attempts to commit such actions as included in Article 4 in the mentioned framework decision.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-traffick</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of child labour and other forms of human trafficking by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Child labour and other forms of human trafficking as defined in Article 2 of the European Parliament and council directive 2011/36/EU of 5. 1 April 2011 on the prevention and control of human trafficking and the protection of its victims and for compensation of the Council ́s framework decision 2002/629/RIA (EUT L 101 of 15.4.2011, p. 1).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-bre-env-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer aware of breaches of environmental provisions as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents or Article 18 (2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-bre-lab-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer aware of breaches of provisions on working conditions as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents or Article 18 (2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-bre-soc-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer aware of breaches of provisions on social conditions as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents or Article 18 (2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-distortion</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer entered into agreement(s) with other tenderers with the intention of turning the competition?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-misconduct</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer committed serious errors in professional practice? If relevant, see the definitions in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-misrepresent</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Have the tenderer:a) given grossly incorrect information when notifying the information required to verify that there is no basis for rejection, or of the qualification requirements being met,b) failed to provide such information,c) subject to immediately submitting the supporting documents requested by the Contracting Authority, ord) improperly affecting the Contracting Authority's decision process to acquire confidential information that could give this an unlawful advantage in connection with competition, or negligently has given misleading information that can have a significant influence on decisions on rejection, selection or award?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-partic-confl</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Are tenderers aware of a conflict of interest as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-prep-confl</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer or an entity associated with the supplier advised the contracting authority or in another way been involved in the planning of the competition?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-sanction</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer committed significant breaches of contract in connection with the fulfilment of a previous public contract, a previous contract with a public contracting authority or a previous concession contract, where the breach has led to the cancellation of the contract, compensation or other similar sanctions?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-natl-bre-nat-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The contracting authority shall state that in Norway there are national rejection reasons. These shall be described in the procurement documents. Tenderers must respond to whether they are in one or more of the situations described in the national rejection reasons. Will the purely national rejection reasons, as stated in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents, apply?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-pmt-bre-ssc</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Have tenderers failed to fulfil all their social security obligations in the country where they are established and in their member state, if this is a different country than what he is established in?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-pmt-bre-tax</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer not fulfilled his tax and duty obligations in the country in which he is established, and in the contracting authority's member state, if this is a different country than what he is established in?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-as-susp</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-bankr</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer in a bankruptcy situation? Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-cred-arran</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the supplier in a situation where he has been forced debt arrangement?  Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-insolvency</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer in an insolvency situation? Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-liq-admin</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the supplier in a situation where he has been forced debt arrangement?  Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
    </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
    <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-grounds-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
    </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
  </cac:TenderingTerms>
  <cac:TenderingProcess>
    
    <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The procurement is for the execution of an engineered solution for safety measures against avalanches from Storefjellet for Honningsvåg centre in Nordkapp municipality. Support superstructures, modified stone warp fences, snow collector screens and rock protection shall be constructed.  The preliminary plan for the security measures is 2025-2028 for honningsvåg centre. The procurement is estimated to have a value of approx. NOK 120,000,000,000 excluding VAT. The estimate is based on previously executed assignments and an assessment of the work to be carried out. The contracting authority is not bound by the estimate.</cbc:Description>
    <cbc:ProcedureCode listName="procurement-procedure-type">open</cbc:ProcedureCode>
    <cac:ProcessJustification>
      <cbc:ProcessReasonCode listName="accelerated-procedure">false</cbc:ProcessReasonCode>
    </cac:ProcessJustification>
  </cac:TenderingProcess>
  <cac:ProcurementProject>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">202512718</cbc:ID>
    
    <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Execution of avalanche protection for honningsvåg centre</cbc:Name>
    
    <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The procurement is for the execution of an engineered solution for safety measures against avalanches from Storefjellet for Honningsvåg centre in Nordkapp municipality. Support superstructures, modified stone warp fences, snow collector screens and rock protection shall be constructed.  The preliminary plan for the security measures is 2025-2028 for honningsvåg centre. The procurement is estimated to have a value of approx. NOK 120,000,000,000 excluding VAT. The estimate is based on previously executed assignments and an assessment of the work to be carried out. The contracting authority is not bound by the estimate.</cbc:Description>
    <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">works</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
    <cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
      <cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount currencyID="NOK">120000000.00</cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount>
    </cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
    <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">45000000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">45220000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">45223000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">45223100</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">45223210</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">45246000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:Address>
        <cbc:CityName>Honningsvåg</cbc:CityName>
        <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO073</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
        <cac:Country>
          <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
        </cac:Country>
      </cac:Address>
    </cac:RealizedLocation>
  </cac:ProcurementProject>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0000</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Requirement for tax certificate. 
Requirement: Tenderers shall have their tax, payroll tax and VAT payments in order.
Documentation requirement: Tax certificate not older than six months from the tender deadline. Tax certificate means: 
Norwegian tenderers: 
A tax and VAT certificate issued by the tax office via Altinn. 

Foreign tenderers: 
Foreign tenderers must submit equivalent certificates from their own country that show that they have an arrangement for the payment of taxes and duties. If the authorities in the relevant country do not issue such certificates, the tenderer shall submit a statement which states that all taxes and duties have been paid. The declaration shall be approved and signed by the tenderer's Financial Director/ person responsible for Finance. 

Tax certificates shall also be submitted for any sub-suppliers who will carry out work under the contract for more than NOK 500,000 excluding VAT, cf. the Public Procurement Regulations § 7-2 third paragraph.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-prof</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Requirements of the tenderer's registrations, authorisations, etc. 
Requirement: The tenderer shall be a legally established company.
Documentation requirement: 
Norwegian tenderers: 
Registration 
Norwegian tenderers do not need to submit a company registration certificate, the contracting authority will obtain this from the Brønnøysund Register Centre itself. 

Foreign tenderers: 
Confirmation that the tenderer is registered in a trade register or company register in accordance with the law in the country where the tenderer is established.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Economic and financial position requirements. 
Requirement: The tenderer shall have sufficient financial strength to be able to fulfil the contract. The financial strength will be assessed in relation to turnover, operating degree, solidity and liquidity. 
Documentation requirement: The tenderer's Annual Financial Statements including notes with the Board's and auditor's reports from 2022 and 2023. Norwegian tenderers do not need to deliver annual accounts, the contracting authority will obtain this from the Brønnøysund Register Centre. 

The Contracting Authority reserves the right to carry out a credit assessment itself. 

If a tenderer has a justifiable reason for not submitting annual accounts, the tenderer can instead document financial strength by presenting other appropriate documentation. For example, recently merged companies may present approved accounts from the companies before the merger.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-ref-work</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Requirements regarding technical and professional qualifications. 
Requirement: Tenderers must have sufficient and relevant experience and competence. 
Documentation requirement: Tenderers shall present an overview of projects/contracts that the tenderer has carried out or carry out during the last 5 years calculated from the tender deadline. At least 2 of the projects shall be described in detail. Documentation of the reference projects shall be filled in the annex "Annex 5 - Template for a description of the reference project". 

The projects/contracts shall, in total, show experience within the following areas: 
- Drilling holes, foundations, assembling and spawning anchors for preliminary buildings against avalanches, rock leaps or similar. Applies to anchoring in uncompacted matter and on rock. 
- Construction/assembly of support extensions (rigid or flexible support extensions) and/or stone warp fences in connection with avalanche protection.  

If the tenderer is planning to use sub-contractors for supporting buildings etc., one or several reference projects shall be carried out by the sub-contractor.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-qu-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Requirements regarding quality assurance standards and environmental management standards. 
Requirement: The tenderer shall be certified or in the process of being certified ISO 9001 or equivalent. 
In the certification process: 
Tenderers shall have a documented quality management system. 

Documentation requirement: A copy of a valid certificate.  
Tenderers in the certification process shall submit:  
- Description of the tenderer's quality assurance methods. 
- Documentation that the process started before the competition was announced together with the final deadline for certification.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-env-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Requirements regarding quality assurance standards and environmental management standards. 
Requirement: Tenderers shall be certified or in the process of being certified ISO 14001, Miljøfyrtårn [Eco-Lighthouse] or equivalent. 
In the certification process: 
Tenderers shall have a documented environment system. 

Documentation requirement: A copy of a valid certificate.  
Tenderers in the certification process shall submit:  
- The table of contents of the company's environment system, in which it is stated (possibly from a detailed description) that the system safeguards the outer environment, cf. the laws, regulations and standards. 
- Documentation that the process started before the competition was announced together with the final deadline for certification.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-sche-qu-cert-indep</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Requirements regarding quality assurance standards and environmental management standards. 
Requirement: The tenderer shall be certified or in the process of being certified ISO 45001 or equivalent. 
In the certification process: 
Tenderers shall have a documented HSE system. 

Documentation requirement: A copy of a valid certificate.  
Tenderers in the certification process shall submit:  
- The table of contents of the company ́s HSE system in which it is stated (possibly from a detailed description) that the system will comply with the requirements in the internal control regulations. 
- Documentation that the process started before the competition was announced together with the final deadline for certification.</cbc:Description>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:FundingProgramCode listName="eu-funded">no-eu-funds</cbc:FundingProgramCode>
      <cbc:MultipleTendersCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:MultipleTendersCode>
      <cac:RequiredFinancialGuarantee>
        <cbc:GuaranteeTypeCode listName="tender-guarantee-required">true</cbc:GuaranteeTypeCode>
      </cac:RequiredFinancialGuarantee>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <ext:UBLExtensions>
          <ext:UBLExtension>
            <ext:ExtensionContent>
              <efext:EformsExtension>
                <efac:OfficialLanguages>
                  <cac:Language>
                    <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
                  </cac:Language>
                </efac:OfficialLanguages>
              </efext:EformsExtension>
            </ext:ExtensionContent>
          </ext:UBLExtension>
        </ext:UBLExtensions>
        <cbc:ID>258781313</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://permalink.mercell.com/258781313.aspx</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">allowed</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="esignature-submission">true</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationParty>
        <cac:PartyIdentification>
          <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
        </cac:PartyIdentification>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationParty>
      <cac:DocumentProviderParty>
        <cac:PartyIdentification>
          <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
        </cac:PartyIdentification>
      </cac:DocumentProviderParty>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://permalink.mercell.com/258781313.aspx</cbc:EndpointID>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="DAY">76</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:TenderValidityPeriod>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">No deadline has been set.</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
      <cac:PostAwardProcess>
        <cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>
        <cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>
      </cac:PostAwardProcess>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-08-01+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:TenderSubmissionDeadlinePeriod>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-06-25+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>14:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationRequestPeriod>
      <cac:OpenTenderEvent>
        <cbc:OccurrenceDate>2025-08-01+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceDate>
        <cbc:OccurrenceTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:OccurrenceTime>
      </cac:OpenTenderEvent>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">202512718</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Execution of avalanche protection for honningsvåg centre</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The procurement is for the execution of an engineered solution for safety measures against avalanches from Storefjellet for Honningsvåg centre in Nordkapp municipality. Support superstructures, modified stone warp fences, snow collector screens and rock protection shall be constructed.  The preliminary plan for the security measures is 2025-2028 for honningsvåg centre. The procurement is estimated to have a value of approx. NOK 120,000,000,000 excluding VAT. The estimate is based on previously executed assignments and an assessment of the work to be carried out. The contracting authority is not bound by the estimate.</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">works</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
        <cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount currencyID="NOK">120000000.00</cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount>
      </cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">45000000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">45220000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">45223000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">45223100</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">45223210</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">45246000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:CityName>Honningsvåg</cbc:CityName>
          <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO073</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
          <cac:Country>
            <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
          </cac:Country>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:StartDate>2025-09-14Z</cbc:StartDate>
        <cbc:EndDate>2028-10-31Z</cbc:EndDate>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
</ContractNotice>