<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><ContractNotice xmlns="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:ContractNotice-2" xmlns:cac="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonAggregateComponents-2" xmlns:cbc="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonBasicComponents-2" xmlns:efac="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extension-aggregate-components/1" xmlns:efbc="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extension-basic-components/1" xmlns:efext="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extensions/1" xmlns:ext="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonExtensionComponents-2">
  <ext:UBLExtensions>
    <ext:UBLExtension>
      <ext:ExtensionContent>
        <efext:EformsExtension>
          <efbc:TransmissionDate>2025-06-04+00:00</efbc:TransmissionDate>
          <efbc:TransmissionTime>13:37:06+00:00</efbc:TransmissionTime>
          <efac:NoticeSubType>
            <cbc:SubTypeCode listName="notice-subtype">16</cbc:SubTypeCode>
          </efac:NoticeSubType>
          <efac:Organizations>
            <efac:Organization>
              <efac:Company>
                <cbc:WebsiteURI>https://www.vegvesen.no</cbc:WebsiteURI>
                <cac:PartyIdentification>
                  <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
                </cac:PartyIdentification>
                
                <cac:PartyName>
                  <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Statens vegvesen</cbc:Name>
                </cac:PartyName>
                <cac:PostalAddress>
                  <cbc:StreetName>Skoggata 19</cbc:StreetName>
                  <cbc:Department>Fellesfunksjoner</cbc:Department>
                  <cbc:CityName>Moss</cbc:CityName>
                  <cbc:PostalZone>1500</cbc:PostalZone>
                  <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO083</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
                  <cac:Country>
                    <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
                  </cac:Country>
                </cac:PostalAddress>
                <cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                  <cbc:CompanyID schemeID="002">971032081</cbc:CompanyID>
                </cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                <cac:Contact>
                  <cbc:Name>Ole Henrik Lidi</cbc:Name>
                  <cbc:Telephone>+47 41556046</cbc:Telephone>
                  <cbc:ElectronicMail>ole.lidi@vegvesen.no</cbc:ElectronicMail>
                </cac:Contact>
              </efac:Company>
            </efac:Organization>
            <efac:Organization>
              <efac:Company>
                <cac:PartyIdentification>
                  <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
                </cac:PartyIdentification>
                
                <cac:PartyName>
                  <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Oslo tingrett</cbc:Name>
                </cac:PartyName>
                <cac:PostalAddress>
                  <cbc:StreetName>C.J. Hambros plass 4</cbc:StreetName>
                  <cbc:CityName>Oslo</cbc:CityName>
                  <cbc:PostalZone>0125</cbc:PostalZone>
                  <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO081</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
                  <cac:Country>
                    <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
                  </cac:Country>
                </cac:PostalAddress>
                <cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                  <cbc:CompanyID schemeID="002">926 725 939</cbc:CompanyID>
                </cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                <cac:Contact>
                  <cbc:Telephone>+47 22035200</cbc:Telephone>
                  <cbc:ElectronicMail>oslo.tingrett@domstol.no</cbc:ElectronicMail>
                </cac:Contact>
              </efac:Company>
            </efac:Organization>
          </efac:Organizations>
        <efac:Publication><efbc:NoticePublicationID schemeName="ojs-notice-id">00368670-2025</efbc:NoticePublicationID><efbc:GazetteID schemeName="ojs-id">108/2025</efbc:GazetteID><efbc:PublicationDate>2025-06-06+02:00</efbc:PublicationDate></efac:Publication></efext:EformsExtension>
      </ext:ExtensionContent>
    </ext:UBLExtension>
  </ext:UBLExtensions>
  <cbc:UBLVersionID>2.3</cbc:UBLVersionID>
  <cbc:CustomizationID>eforms-sdk-1.13</cbc:CustomizationID>
  <cbc:ID schemeName="notice-id">22234c16-3a37-44a2-9989-4f74373ffd6d</cbc:ID>
  <cbc:ContractFolderID>e3fa107c-7ce8-42e0-915e-53442e00dc26</cbc:ContractFolderID>
  <cbc:IssueDate>2025-06-04+00:00</cbc:IssueDate>
  <cbc:IssueTime>13:25:22+00:00</cbc:IssueTime>
  <cbc:VersionID>01</cbc:VersionID>
  <cbc:RegulatoryDomain>32014L0024</cbc:RegulatoryDomain>
  <cbc:NoticeTypeCode listName="competition">cn-standard</cbc:NoticeTypeCode>
  <cbc:NoticeLanguageCode>ENG</cbc:NoticeLanguageCode>
  
  <cac:ContractingParty>
    <cbc:BuyerProfileURI>https://eu.eu-supply.com/ctm/company/companyinformation/index/249176</cbc:BuyerProfileURI>
    <cac:ContractingPartyType>
      <cbc:PartyTypeCode listName="buyer-legal-type">body-pl-cga</cbc:PartyTypeCode>
    </cac:ContractingPartyType>
    <cac:ContractingActivity>
      <cbc:ActivityTypeCode listName="authority-activity">gen-pub</cbc:ActivityTypeCode>
    </cac:ContractingActivity>
    <cac:Party>
      <cac:PartyIdentification>
        <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
      </cac:PartyIdentification>
    </cac:Party>
  </cac:ContractingParty>
  <cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-corrpt</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a enforceable verdict has been convicted of corruption by a verdict handed down not more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Corruption as defined in Article 3 of the Convention on Combating Corruption, Involving European Communities or European Union Member States (EUT C 195 of 25.6.1997, s. 1), and in Article 2, point 1, in the Council ́s framework decision 2003/568/RIA of 22 July 2003 on combating corruption in the private sector (EUT L 192 of 31.7.2003,  p. 54). This rejection reason also includes corruption as defined in national law for the contracting authority or supplier.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-fraud</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, at the time a legally convicted of fraud has been convicted of fraud by a verdict handed down not more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Fraud included in Article 1 of the Convention on protection of the Financial Interests of the European Communities (EFT C 316 of 27.11.1995, p. 48).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-laund</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of money laundering or financing terrorism by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Money laundering or financing terrorism As defined in Article 1 of the European Parliament and Council Directive 2005/60/EF of 26 October 2005 on preventive measures against the use of the financial system for money laundering and financing terrorism (EUT L 309 of 25.11.2005, p. 15).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-part</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, at the time a legally convicted verdict of participation in a criminal organisation by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Participation in a criminal organisation as defined in Article 2 of the Council ́s framework decision 2008/841/RIA of 24 October 2008 on control of organised crime (EUT L 300 of 11.11.2008, p. 42)</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-terror</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body, or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of acts of terrorism or criminal acts connected to terrorist activities by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Acts of terrorism or criminal acts relating to terrorist activity as defined in Article 1 and 3 of the Council ́s framework decision 2002/475/RIA of 13 June 2002 on combating terrorism (EFT L 164, af 22.6.2002, p. 3). This rejection reason also includes incitement to, participation or attempts to commit such actions as included in Article 4 in the mentioned framework decision.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-traffick</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of child labour and other forms of human trafficking by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Child labour and other forms of human trafficking as defined in Article 2 of the European Parliament and council directive 2011/36/EU of 5. 1 April 2011 on the prevention and control of human trafficking and the protection of its victims and for compensation of the Council ́s framework decision 2002/629/RIA (EUT L 101 of 15.4.2011, p. 1).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-bre-env-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer aware of breaches of environmental provisions as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents or Article 18 (2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-bre-lab-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer aware of breaches of provisions on working conditions as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents or Article 18 (2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-bre-soc-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer aware of breaches of provisions on social conditions as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents or Article 18 (2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-distortion</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer entered into agreement(s) with other tenderers with the intention of turning the competition?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-misconduct</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer committed serious errors in professional practice? If relevant, see the definitions in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-misrepresent</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Have the tenderer:a) given grossly incorrect information when notifying the information required to verify that there is no basis for rejection, or of the qualification requirements being met,b) failed to provide such information,c) subject to immediately submitting the supporting documents requested by the Contracting Authority, ord) improperly affecting the Contracting Authority's decision process to acquire confidential information that could give this an unlawful advantage in connection with competition, or negligently has given misleading information that can have a significant influence on decisions on rejection, selection or award?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-partic-confl</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Are tenderers aware of a conflict of interest as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-prep-confl</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer or an entity associated with the supplier advised the contracting authority or in another way been involved in the planning of the competition?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-sanction</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer committed significant breaches of contract in connection with the fulfilment of a previous public contract, a previous contract with a public contracting authority or a previous concession contract, where the breach has led to the cancellation of the contract, compensation or other similar sanctions?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-natl-bre-nat-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Approved procedures for staffing conditions
Does the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body, or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, approved procedures for some of the punishable conditions mentioned above, j.f. the Procurement Regulations § 24-2, (2) paragraph, a-f?

Serious errors that cause doubt about his professional integrity
Has the tenderer otherwise committed serious errors that cause doubt about his professional integrity, cf.f. the procurement regulations § 24-2, (3) letter in?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-pmt-bre-ssc</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Have tenderers failed to fulfil all their social security obligations in the country where they are established and in their member state, if this is a different country than what he is established in?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-pmt-bre-tax</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer not fulfilled his tax and duty obligations in the country in which he is established, and in the contracting authority's member state, if this is a different country than what he is established in?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-as-susp</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-bankr</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer in a bankruptcy situation? Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-cred-arran</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the supplier in a situation where he has been forced debt arrangement?  Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-insolvency</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer in an insolvency situation? Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-liq-admin</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the supplier in a situation where he has been forced debt arrangement?  Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
    </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
    <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-grounds-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
    </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
  </cac:TenderingTerms>
  <cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cbc:ProcedureCode listName="procurement-procedure-type">neg-w-call</cbc:ProcedureCode>
    <cac:ProcessJustification>
      <cbc:ProcessReasonCode listName="accelerated-procedure">false</cbc:ProcessReasonCode>
    </cac:ProcessJustification>
  </cac:TenderingProcess>
  <cac:ProcurementProject>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">24/317220</cbc:ID>
    
    <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Procurement of a system for telephone exchanges and call centres.</cbc:Name>
    
    <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The Norwegian Public Roads Administration needs to procure a cloud based switchboard and call centre system.

The system shall first and foremost cover the Norwegian Public Roads Administration ́s need for handling enquiries by using telephony as well as a channel, as well as SMS for outgoing enquiries to customers. The system shall, however, also allow for other channels such as chat, email and social media to be in use during the agreement period. 

The aim is to procure a system that contributes to a better user experience for the Norwegian Public Roads Administration ́s customers. Customers should be able to use their most preferred channel when they contact and they shall find that the Norwegian Public Roads Administration has a good overview and is available so that they can quickly get answers to their enquiries. At the same time, customers should feel confident that their privacy is safeguarded. 

In order to deliver good user experiences for the Norwegian Public Roads Administration ́s customers, the system shall also facilitate efficient work processes that make it easy and quick to help and guide customers. The system shall be used by a large number of agents. It is therefore important that the solution is experienced as intuitive as possible, including that screen images and number of clicks are reduced to a minimum.

The system shall also provide good work support to the Norwegian Public Roads Administration ́s administrators. It shall be easy to share relevant information to customers and they shall have a tool for simpler administration and allocation of resources/agents as well as a tool for reporting and analysing customer enquiries.</cbc:Description>
    <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
    <cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
      <cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount currencyID="NOK">45000000</cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount>
    </cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
    <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">79512000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">32543000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">48510000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">50334400</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">64214200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72000000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72212211</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72212510</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72212511</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:Address>
        <cbc:Region>anyw-eea</cbc:Region>
      </cac:Address>
    </cac:RealizedLocation>
  </cac:ProcurementProject>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0000</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-ref-supply</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers shall have relevant experience.

The following central works/areas are particularly relevant:
Delivery, implementation and operation of a switchboard and call centre system in large organisations.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall confirm that they fulfil this requirement when submitting their qualification enquiry.

Tenderers shall present the following documentation proof if requested by the contracting authority:
- An overview of at least 3 (maximum 5) of the most important, relevant work performed during the last three years, including a short description of the assignment, the name of the public or private recipient, as well as information on the time frame and value/scope. 

If it is necessary to ensure a sufficient competition, the contracting authority can state that also documentation of relevant deliveries or services that the tenderer has carried out more than three years ago will be considered.</cbc:Description>
                <efbc:SecondStageIndicator>true</efbc:SecondStageIndicator>
                <efac:CriterionParameter>
                  <efbc:ParameterCode listName="number-weight">per-exa</efbc:ParameterCode>
                  <efbc:ParameterNumeric>100</efbc:ParameterNumeric>
                </efac:CriterionParameter>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-trade</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The tenderer shall be a legally established company.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall confirm that they fulfil this requirement when submitting their qualification enquiry.

Tenderers shall present the following documentation proof if requested by the contracting authority:
• Norwegian tenderers: Company Registration Certificate.
• Foreign tenderers: Documentation proving that the company is registered in a trade or business register as prescribed by the law of the country where the tenderer is established.</cbc:Description>
                <efbc:SecondStageIndicator>false</efbc:SecondStageIndicator>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers must have sufficient financial capacity to fulfil the contract. 
Creditworthiness will be sufficient to meet the requirement.

Documentation requirement:
The contracting authority will obtain a credit rating from Experian. 
If there is doubt, the Contracting Authority can obtain further information from the tenderer.</cbc:Description>
                <efbc:SecondStageIndicator>false</efbc:SecondStageIndicator>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers shall have their tax, payroll tax and VAT payments in order.

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall confirm that they fulfil this requirement when submitting their qualification enquiry.

Tenderers shall, upon request by the Contracting Authority, present a tax and VAT certificate issued by a competent body in the tenderer's home country or the country where the tenderer is established. The certificate shall show whether the tenderer has fulfilled his obligations to pay taxes, duties and social security contributions. 

The certificate shall not be older than six months from the tender deadline. If a request for participation in the competition is to be submitted, the certificate must not be older than six months calculated from the deadline for submitting the enquiry.</cbc:Description>
                <efbc:SecondStageIndicator>false</efbc:SecondStageIndicator>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">According to the regulation on restrictive measures regarding actions that undermine or threaten Ukraine's territorial integrity, sovereignty, independence and stability (The Sanctions Regulations of Ukraine (territorial integrity etc.)) § 8n, it is forbidden to award, or continue the implementation of public contracts above the EEA threshold value of, and with, Russian actors.  

Tenderers shall not be a unit that is under the ban in the Sanctions Regulations of Ukraine (territorial integrity etc.) § 8n.   

Documentation requirement:
Tenderers shall confirm that they fulfil this requirement when submitting their qualification enquiry. 

The contracting authority has the right to carry out the investigations that are necessary to ensure fulfilment of the sanctions regulations in the competition implementation and in the contract period. Tenderers shall, upon request from the Contracting Authority, assist in the work and present relevant documentation that enables the Contracting Authority to assess whether the Tenderer is affected by the ban.</cbc:Description>
                <efbc:SecondStageIndicator>false</efbc:SecondStageIndicator>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:FundingProgramCode listName="eu-funded">no-eu-funds</cbc:FundingProgramCode>
      <cbc:MultipleTendersCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:MultipleTendersCode>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <cbc:ID>Anskaffelsesdokumenter</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://eu.eu-supply.com/app/rfq/rwlentrance_s.asp?PID=433259&amp;B=</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">not-allowed</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:AwardingTerms>
        <cbc:NoFurtherNegotiationIndicator>false</cbc:NoFurtherNegotiationIndicator>
        <cac:AwardingCriterion>
          <cac:SubordinateAwardingCriterion>
            <ext:UBLExtensions>
              <ext:UBLExtension>
                <ext:ExtensionContent>
                  <efext:EformsExtension>
                    <efac:AwardCriterionParameter>
                      <efbc:ParameterCode listName="number-weight">per-exa</efbc:ParameterCode>
                      <efbc:ParameterNumeric>70</efbc:ParameterNumeric>
                    </efac:AwardCriterionParameter>
                  </efext:EformsExtension>
                </ext:ExtensionContent>
              </ext:UBLExtension>
            </ext:UBLExtensions>
            <cbc:AwardingCriterionTypeCode listName="award-criterion-type">quality</cbc:AwardingCriterionTypeCode>
            
            <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Quality</cbc:Name>
            
            <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">- Fulfilment of the functional, cf. The tenderer ́s response to the Customer's Annex 1, annex 3. 
- Fulfilment of the non-functional requirements, cf. The tenderer ́s response to the Customer's Annex 1, annex 3. 
- Fulfilment of establishment and training requirements, cf. The tenderer ́s response to the Customer's Annex 3. 
- Fulfilment of service level requirements, cf. The tenderer ́s response to the Customer's Annexes 4 and 9.

See also the document "Information and rules for the procurement" for a further description of the award criteria.</cbc:Description>
          </cac:SubordinateAwardingCriterion>
          <cac:SubordinateAwardingCriterion>
            <ext:UBLExtensions>
              <ext:UBLExtension>
                <ext:ExtensionContent>
                  <efext:EformsExtension>
                    <efac:AwardCriterionParameter>
                      <efbc:ParameterCode listName="number-weight">per-exa</efbc:ParameterCode>
                      <efbc:ParameterNumeric>30</efbc:ParameterNumeric>
                    </efac:AwardCriterionParameter>
                  </efext:EformsExtension>
                </ext:ExtensionContent>
              </ext:UBLExtension>
            </ext:UBLExtensions>
            <cbc:AwardingCriterionTypeCode listName="award-criterion-type">price</cbc:AwardingCriterionTypeCode>
            
            <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Total price for the maximum duration of the agreement</cbc:Name>
            
            <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The tenderer ́s response to the Customer ́s annex 6:
- Point 6.1.1, Remuneration for the establishment project
- Point 6.1,2, Remuneration for the service.
- Point 6.1.3, Remuneration for options (absolute)
- Point 6.2, Further development after delivery day.

See also the document "Information and rules for the procurement" for a further description of the award criteria.

See also the document "Information and rules for the procurement" for a further description of the award criteria.</cbc:Description>
          </cac:SubordinateAwardingCriterion>
          <cac:SubordinateAwardingCriterion>
            <ext:UBLExtensions>
              <ext:UBLExtension>
                <ext:ExtensionContent>
                  <efext:EformsExtension>
                    <efac:AwardCriterionParameter>
                      <efbc:ParameterCode listName="number-weight">per-exa</efbc:ParameterCode>
                      <efbc:ParameterNumeric>0</efbc:ParameterNumeric>
                    </efac:AwardCriterionParameter>
                  </efext:EformsExtension>
                </ext:ExtensionContent>
              </ext:UBLExtension>
            </ext:UBLExtensions>
            <cbc:AwardingCriterionTypeCode listName="award-criterion-type">quality</cbc:AwardingCriterionTypeCode>
            
            <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Immaterial climate footprint and environmental impact (justified below)</cbc:Name>
            
            <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Requirements and criteria set pursuant to the procurement regulations § 7-9 shall aim at reducing the procurement ́s total climate footprint or environmental impact, cf. the procurement regulations § 7-9 (1). The main rule in the procurement regulations § 7-9 (2) is that the contracting authority shall emphasise climate and environmental considerations with a minimum of thirty percent. Exceptions from the obligation to set environmental requirements or criteria exist if the procurement has, in its nature, a climate footprint and an environmental impact that is immaterial and this is justified in the procurement documents, cf. the procurement regulations § 7-9 (5).

The Need of the Norwegian Public Roads Administration shall primarily be covered through a cloud service in order to handle customer enquiries in different channels. Furthermore, the procurement involves maintenance and further development of such a service, operation and use of the service. The work on maintenance and further development of the service can be compared with a consultancy service without particular travel activities and is therefore considered to have immaterial climate footprint and environmental impact.

Based on this, the procurement is being assessed by a switchboard and call centre system to have immaterial climate footprint and environmental impact, cf. FOA § 7-9 (5).  

Although the procurement is assessed to have immaterial climate footprint and environmental impact, we see that the data centres used to operate the systems can have possible climate footprint and environmental impact. The tenderer's influence over this energy consumption and the possible environmental impact is, however, very limited, and it means that it is aimless for the Norwegian Public Roads Administration to emphasise or set requirements in the requirement specifications for climate and the environment in this procurement. This does not change, therefore, on the assessment that the Public Procurement Regulations § 7-9 (5) will be used in this procurement.</cbc:Description>
          </cac:SubordinateAwardingCriterion>
        </cac:AwardingCriterion>
      </cac:AwardingTerms>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://eu.eu-supply.com/app/rfq/rwlentrance_s.asp?PID=433259&amp;B=</cbc:EndpointID>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">In accordance with the national regulations.</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
      <cac:PostAwardProcess>
        <cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>false</cbc:ElectronicOrderUsageIndicator>
        <cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>true</cbc:ElectronicPaymentUsageIndicator>
      </cac:PostAwardProcess>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:CandidateReductionConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:CandidateReductionConstraintIndicator>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:ParticipationRequestReceptionPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-07-07+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:ParticipationRequestReceptionPeriod>
      <cac:EconomicOperatorShortList>
        <cbc:LimitationDescription>true</cbc:LimitationDescription>
        <cbc:MaximumQuantity>5</cbc:MaximumQuantity>
        <cbc:MinimumQuantity>3</cbc:MinimumQuantity>
      </cac:EconomicOperatorShortList>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">24/317220</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Procurement of a system for telephone exchanges and call centres.</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The Norwegian Public Roads Administration needs to procure a cloud based switchboard and call centre system.

The system shall first and foremost cover the Norwegian Public Roads Administration ́s need for handling enquiries by using telephony as well as a channel, as well as SMS for outgoing enquiries to customers. The system shall, however, also allow for other channels such as chat, email and social media to be in use during the agreement period. 

The aim is to procure a system that contributes to a better user experience for the Norwegian Public Roads Administration ́s customers. Customers should be able to use their most preferred channel when they contact and they shall find that the Norwegian Public Roads Administration has a good overview and is available so that they can quickly get answers to their enquiries. At the same time, customers should feel confident that their privacy is safeguarded. 

In order to deliver good user experiences for the Norwegian Public Roads Administration ́s customers, the system shall also facilitate efficient work processes that make it easy and quick to help and guide customers. The system shall be used by a large number of agents. It is therefore important that the solution is experienced as intuitive as possible, including that screen images and number of clicks are reduced to a minimum.

The system shall also provide good work support to the Norwegian Public Roads Administration ́s administrators. It shall be easy to share relevant information to customers and they shall have a tool for simpler administration and allocation of resources/agents as well as a tool for reporting and analysing customer enquiries.</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
        <cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount currencyID="NOK">45000000</cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount>
      </cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">79512000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">32543000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">48510000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">50334400</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">64214200</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72000000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72212211</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72212510</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72212511</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:Region>anyw-eea</cbc:Region>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="YEAR">10</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
      <cac:ContractExtension>
        <cbc:MaximumNumberNumeric>7</cbc:MaximumNumberNumeric>
        <cac:Renewal>
          <cac:Period>
            
            <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The contract will be valid for 3 (three) years calculated from the delivery day. Option for a contract extension for 1+1+1+1+1+1+1+1 year.</cbc:Description>
          </cac:Period>
        </cac:Renewal>
      </cac:ContractExtension>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
</ContractNotice>