<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><ContractNotice xmlns="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:ContractNotice-2" xmlns:cac="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonAggregateComponents-2" xmlns:cbc="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonBasicComponents-2" xmlns:efac="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extension-aggregate-components/1" xmlns:efbc="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extension-basic-components/1" xmlns:efext="http://data.europa.eu/p27/eforms-ubl-extensions/1" xmlns:ext="urn:oasis:names:specification:ubl:schema:xsd:CommonExtensionComponents-2">
  <ext:UBLExtensions>
    <ext:UBLExtension>
      <ext:ExtensionContent>
        <efext:EformsExtension>
          <efbc:TransmissionDate>2025-06-05+00:00</efbc:TransmissionDate>
          <efbc:TransmissionTime>09:02:56+00:00</efbc:TransmissionTime>
          <efac:NoticeSubType>
            <cbc:SubTypeCode listName="notice-subtype">17</cbc:SubTypeCode>
          </efac:NoticeSubType>
          <efac:Organizations>
            <efac:Organization>
              <efac:Company>
                <cbc:WebsiteURI>https://www.trondheim.kommune.no</cbc:WebsiteURI>
                <cac:PartyIdentification>
                  <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
                </cac:PartyIdentification>
                
                <cac:PartyName>
                  <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Trondheim kommune</cbc:Name>
                </cac:PartyName>
                <cac:PostalAddress>
                  <cbc:StreetName>Erling Skakkes gate 14</cbc:StreetName>
                  <cbc:CityName>TRONDHEIM</cbc:CityName>
                  <cbc:PostalZone>7004</cbc:PostalZone>
                  <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO060</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
                  <cac:Country>
                    <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
                  </cac:Country>
                </cac:PostalAddress>
                <cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                  <cbc:CompanyID schemeID="002">942110464</cbc:CompanyID>
                </cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                <cac:Contact>
                  <cbc:Name>Maria Melkeraaen Skjervold</cbc:Name>
                  <cbc:Telephone>+47 72540000</cbc:Telephone>
                  <cbc:ElectronicMail>maria.melkeraaen.skjervold@trondheim.kommune.no</cbc:ElectronicMail>
                </cac:Contact>
              </efac:Company>
            </efac:Organization>
            <efac:Organization>
              <efac:Company>
                <cac:PartyIdentification>
                  <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
                </cac:PartyIdentification>
                
                <cac:PartyName>
                  <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Trøndelag tingrett</cbc:Name>
                </cac:PartyName>
                <cac:PostalAddress>
                  <cbc:StreetName>Postboks 2300 Torgarden</cbc:StreetName>
                  <cbc:Department>TRONDHEIM KOMMUNE</cbc:Department>
                  <cbc:CityName>TRONDHEIM</cbc:CityName>
                  <cbc:PostalZone>7004</cbc:PostalZone>
                  <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO060</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
                  <cac:Country>
                    <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
                  </cac:Country>
                </cac:PostalAddress>
                <cac:PartyLegalEntity>
                  <cbc:CompanyID schemeID="002">926 722 794</cbc:CompanyID>
                </cac:PartyLegalEntity>
              </efac:Company>
            </efac:Organization>
          </efac:Organizations>
        <efac:Publication><efbc:NoticePublicationID schemeName="ojs-notice-id">00367306-2025</efbc:NoticePublicationID><efbc:GazetteID schemeName="ojs-id">108/2025</efbc:GazetteID><efbc:PublicationDate>2025-06-06+02:00</efbc:PublicationDate></efac:Publication></efext:EformsExtension>
      </ext:ExtensionContent>
    </ext:UBLExtension>
  </ext:UBLExtensions>
  <cbc:UBLVersionID>2.3</cbc:UBLVersionID>
  <cbc:CustomizationID>eforms-sdk-1.13</cbc:CustomizationID>
  <cbc:ID schemeName="notice-id">2f1592b5-883d-4e64-b87e-b1954f02aa83</cbc:ID>
  <cbc:ContractFolderID>7d7314a0-af04-4df2-b23a-d9507d683e41</cbc:ContractFolderID>
  <cbc:IssueDate>2025-06-05+00:00</cbc:IssueDate>
  <cbc:IssueTime>08:34:17+00:00</cbc:IssueTime>
  <cbc:VersionID>01</cbc:VersionID>
  <cbc:RegulatoryDomain>32014L0025</cbc:RegulatoryDomain>
  <cbc:NoticeTypeCode listName="competition">cn-standard</cbc:NoticeTypeCode>
  <cbc:NoticeLanguageCode>ENG</cbc:NoticeLanguageCode>
  
  <cac:ContractingParty>
    <cac:ContractingActivity>
      <cbc:ActivityTypeCode listName="entity-activity">water</cbc:ActivityTypeCode>
    </cac:ContractingActivity>
    <cac:Party>
      <cac:PartyIdentification>
        <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
      </cac:PartyIdentification>
    </cac:Party>
  </cac:ContractingParty>
  <cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:ProcurementLegislationDocumentReference>
      <cbc:ID>Forsyningsforskriften</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:DocumentDescription languageID="ENG">The contract award will be made following the procedure: competition with negotiation after prior notification, cf. PPR § 9-1, first paragraph.</cbc:DocumentDescription>
    </cac:ProcurementLegislationDocumentReference>
    <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-corrpt</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a enforceable verdict has been convicted of corruption by a verdict handed down not more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Corruption as defined in Article 3 of the Convention on Combating Corruption, Involving European Communities or European Union Member States (EUT C 195 of 25.6.1997, s. 1), and in Article 2, point 1, in the Council ́s framework decision 2003/568/RIA of 22 July 2003 on combating corruption in the private sector (EUT L 192 of 31.7.2003,  p. 54). This rejection reason also includes corruption as defined in national law for the contracting authority or supplier.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-fraud</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, at the time a legally convicted of fraud has been convicted of fraud by a verdict handed down not more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Fraud included in Article 1 of the Convention on protection of the Financial Interests of the European Communities (EFT C 316 of 27.11.1995, p. 48).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-laund</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of money laundering or financing terrorism by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Money laundering or financing terrorism As defined in Article 1 of the European Parliament and Council Directive 2005/60/EF of 26 October 2005 on preventive measures against the use of the financial system for money laundering and financing terrorism (EUT L 309 of 25.11.2005, p. 15).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-part</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, at the time a legally convicted verdict of participation in a criminal organisation by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Participation in a criminal organisation as defined in Article 2 of the Council ́s framework decision 2008/841/RIA of 24 October 2008 on control of organised crime (EUT L 300 of 11.11.2008, p. 42)</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-terror</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body, or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of acts of terrorism or criminal acts connected to terrorist activities by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period set out directly in the judgement that still applies? Acts of terrorism or criminal acts relating to terrorist activity as defined in Article 1 and 3 of the Council ́s framework decision 2002/475/RIA of 13 June 2002 on combating terrorism (EFT L 164, af 22.6.2002, p. 3). This rejection reason also includes incitement to, participation or attempts to commit such actions as included in Article 4 in the mentioned framework decision.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-crim-traffick</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer himself or a person, who is a member of the tenderer's administration, management or supervisory body or has the competence to represent or control or make decisions in such bodies, in the event a legal verdict has been convicted of child labour and other forms of human trafficking by a verdict handed down no more than five years ago, or a rejection period determined directly in the judgement that still applies? Child labour and other forms of human trafficking as defined in Article 2 of the European Parliament and council directive 2011/36/EU of 5. 1 April 2011 on the prevention and control of human trafficking and the protection of its victims and for compensation of the Council ́s framework decision 2002/629/RIA (EUT L 101 of 15.4.2011, p. 1).</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-bre-env-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer aware of breaches of environmental provisions as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents or Article 18 (2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-bre-lab-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer aware of breaches of provisions on working conditions as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents or Article 18 (2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-bre-soc-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer aware of breaches of provisions on social conditions as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents or Article 18 (2) of Directive 2014/24/EU.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-distortion</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer entered into agreement(s) with other tenderers with the intention of turning the competition?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-misconduct</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer committed serious errors in professional practice? If relevant, see the definitions in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-misrepresent</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Have the tenderer:a) given grossly incorrect information when notifying the information required to verify that there is no basis for rejection, or of the qualification requirements being met,b) failed to provide such information,c) subject to immediately submitting the supporting documents requested by the Contracting Authority, ord) improperly affecting the Contracting Authority's decision process to acquire confidential information that could give this an unlawful advantage in connection with competition, or negligently has given misleading information that can have a significant influence on decisions on rejection, selection or award?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-partic-confl</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Are tenderers aware of a conflict of interest as stated in national law, the relevant notice or procurement documents?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-prep-confl</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer or an entity associated with the supplier advised the contracting authority or in another way been involved in the planning of the competition?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-mis-sanction</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer committed significant breaches of contract in connection with the fulfilment of a previous public contract, a previous contract with a public contracting authority or a previous concession contract, where the breach has led to the cancellation of the contract, compensation or other similar sanctions?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-natl-bre-nat-law</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The contracting authority shall state that in Norway there are national rejection reasons. These shall be described in the procurement documents. Tenderers must respond to whether they are in one or more of the situations described in the national rejection reasons. Will the purely national rejection reasons, as stated in the relevant notice or in the procurement documents, apply?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-pmt-bre-ssc</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Have tenderers failed to fulfil all their social security obligations in the country where they are established and in their member state, if this is a different country than what he is established in?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-pmt-bre-tax</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Has the tenderer not fulfilled his tax and duty obligations in the country in which he is established, and in the contracting authority's member state, if this is a different country than what he is established in?</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-as-susp</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-bankr</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer in a bankruptcy situation? Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-cred-arran</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the supplier in a situation where he has been forced debt arrangement?  Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-insolvency</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the tenderer in an insolvency situation? Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-liq-admin</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-ground">exg-sitn-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Is the supplier in a situation where he has been forced debt arrangement?  Specify why, under the mentioned circumstances, one is able to carry out the contract, considering the current national provisions and measures for continuing the business activities? It is not necessary to provide this information if rejection of tenderers made mandatory in accordance with the current national law without the possibility for exceptions.</cbc:Description>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
    </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
    <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
        <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="exclusion-grounds-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
      </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
    </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
  </cac:TenderingTerms>
  <cac:TenderingProcess>
    
    <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Trondheim Municipality is seeking proposals for cloud-based software solutions that can improve the operation and management of its water distribution and sewerage networks. The municipality aims to achieve the following objectives: Reduce Water Loss: Lower water loss in the water distribution network to below 20% by 2030 by identifying and repairing leaks in both municipal and private pipes. Optimize Sewerage Network: Reduce the volume of extraneous water in the sewerage system by identifying and prioritising the largest sources and optimising sewage management to minimise outflow and overflow into recipients. We invite qualified providers to submit proposals detailing software solutions that address one or both of these objectives. Integrated solutions for both water distribution and sewage management are preferred, but solutions tailored to either field individually are also of interest. The value of the contract is estimated at NOK 10 million excluding VAT, including options. The estimated contract value is for information purposes only and the contraction authority is not bound by it. OptionsThe tender includes options for hydrological models and data sharing / API functionality, as well as annual support/ development during both project and operations.</cbc:Description>
    <cbc:ProcedureCode listName="procurement-procedure-type">neg-w-call</cbc:ProcedureCode>
    <cac:ProcessJustification>
      <cbc:ProcessReasonCode listName="accelerated-procedure">false</cbc:ProcessReasonCode>
    </cac:ProcessJustification>
  </cac:TenderingProcess>
  <cac:ProcurementProject>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025/12360</cbc:ID>
    
    <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Step 1 - Procurement of "Software for leakage reduction and sewerage system outflow in Municipality of Trondheim" - Prequalification</cbc:Name>
    
    <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Trondheim Municipality, hereinafter referred to as the contracting authority, invites tenders for a contract in the project ""Software for Leakage Reduction and Sewerage System Outflow in Municipality of Trondheim".</cbc:Description>
    <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
    <cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
      <cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount currencyID="NOK">10000000.00</cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount>
    </cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
    <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72000000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">48000000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">48100000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">48600000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72300000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
    </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
    <cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:Address>
        <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO060</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
        <cac:Country>
          <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
        </cac:Country>
      </cac:Address>
    </cac:RealizedLocation>
  </cac:ProcurementProject>
  <cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
    <cbc:ID schemeName="Lot">LOT-0000</cbc:ID>
    <cac:TenderingTerms>
      <ext:UBLExtensions>
        <ext:UBLExtension>
          <ext:ExtensionContent>
            <efext:EformsExtension>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-suit-reg-trade</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers are registered in a company register or a trade register in the member state in which the tenderer is established. As described in annex XI of directive 2014/24/EU; suppliers from certain member states may have to fulfil other requirements in the mentioned annex.
Minimum qualification requirements
Minimum requirement: Tenderers shall be legally registered in a company register or a commerce register in the country where the tenderer is established. 
Documentation requirement: Norwegian companies shall have a Company Registration Certificate. Foreign companies shall have registration certificates in professional registers as determined by legislation in the country where the tenderer is established.</cbc:Description>
                <efbc:SecondStageIndicator>true</efbc:SecondStageIndicator>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Regarding any other economic and financial requirements that have been stated in the notice or in the procurement documents, the tenderer declares that:
Minimum qualification requirements
Requirement: Tenderers shall have sufficient economic and financial capacity to fulfil the contract. Tenderers shall be credit worthy. Documentation requirement: Credit evaluation/rating, not older than 3 months, based on the last known accounting figures. The rating shall be carried out by a publicly certified credit rating institution. If the tenderer has a justifiable reason for not submitting the documentation required by the contracting authority, he can document his economic and financial capacity by presenting other documentation.</cbc:Description>
                <efbc:SecondStageIndicator>true</efbc:SecondStageIndicator>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-abil-ref-services</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Only for services: In the reference period, the tenderer has carried out the following important goods deliveries of the requested type, or the following important services of the requested type. The contracting authority can require up to three years experience and allow experience from the previous three years to be taken into consideration.
Minimum qualification requirements
Requirement: Tenderers shall have experience from equivalent deliveries from other contracting authorities. Documentation requirement: A description of at least one equivalent delivery for other customers, from the last three years that are still in use at the contracting authority. The documentation must include a statement of the contract ́s value, date of delivery and recipient (name, telephone number and e-mail address). References can be contacted for verification of the information.</cbc:Description>
                <efbc:SecondStageIndicator>true</efbc:SecondStageIndicator>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
              <efac:SelectionCriteria>
                <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criterion">slc-stand-other</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
                
                <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Tenderers shall have their tax and duty payments in order. Documentation requirement: Tax certificate. The certificate shall not be older than six months, from expiry of the tender deadline. Foreign tenderers must provide certificates from equivalent authorities in the countries where they are registered for tax. If the authorities in the relevant country do not issue such certificates, the tenderer must submit a signed self-declaration as to whether tax arrears and any size thereof are arrears.</cbc:Description>
                <efbc:SecondStageIndicator>true</efbc:SecondStageIndicator>
              </efac:SelectionCriteria>
            </efext:EformsExtension>
          </ext:ExtensionContent>
        </ext:UBLExtension>
      </ext:UBLExtensions>
      <cbc:VariantConstraintCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:VariantConstraintCode>
      <cbc:MultipleTendersCode listName="permission">not-allowed</cbc:MultipleTendersCode>
      <cac:RequiredFinancialGuarantee>
        <cbc:GuaranteeTypeCode listName="tender-guarantee-required">false</cbc:GuaranteeTypeCode>
      </cac:RequiredFinancialGuarantee>
      <cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
        <ext:UBLExtensions>
          <ext:UBLExtension>
            <ext:ExtensionContent>
              <efext:EformsExtension>
                <efac:OfficialLanguages>
                  <cac:Language>
                    <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
                  </cac:Language>
                </efac:OfficialLanguages>
              </efext:EformsExtension>
            </ext:ExtensionContent>
          </ext:UBLExtension>
        </ext:UBLExtensions>
        <cbc:ID>258109627</cbc:ID>
        <cbc:DocumentType>non-restricted-document</cbc:DocumentType>
        <cac:Attachment>
          <cac:ExternalReference>
            <cbc:URI>https://permalink.mercell.com/258109627.aspx</cbc:URI>
          </cac:ExternalReference>
        </cac:Attachment>
      </cac:CallForTendersDocumentReference>
      <cac:PaymentTerms>
        
        <cbc:Note languageID="ENG">See the tender documentation</cbc:Note>
      </cac:PaymentTerms>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="selection-criteria-source">epo-notice</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
          <cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode listName="reserved-procurement">none</cbc:TendererRequirementTypeCode>
        </cac:SpecificTendererRequirement>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
        <cbc:CompanyLegalFormCode listName="required">false</cbc:CompanyLegalFormCode>
      </cac:TendererQualificationRequest>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="einvoicing">required</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="reserved-execution">no</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="ecatalog-submission">not-allowed</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="esignature-submission">false</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
        <cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode listName="conditions">performance</cbc:ExecutionRequirementCode>
        
        <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">See the tender documentation</cbc:Description>
      </cac:ContractExecutionRequirement>
      <cac:AwardingTerms>
        <cac:AwardingCriterion>
          <cac:SubordinateAwardingCriterion>
            <ext:UBLExtensions>
              <ext:UBLExtension>
                <ext:ExtensionContent>
                  <efext:EformsExtension>
                    <efac:AwardCriterionParameter>
                      <efbc:ParameterCode listName="number-weight">per-exa</efbc:ParameterCode>
                      <efbc:ParameterNumeric>30</efbc:ParameterNumeric>
                    </efac:AwardCriterionParameter>
                  </efext:EformsExtension>
                </ext:ExtensionContent>
              </ext:UBLExtension>
            </ext:UBLExtensions>
            <cbc:AwardingCriterionTypeCode listName="award-criterion-type">price</cbc:AwardingCriterionTypeCode>
            
            <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Price</cbc:Name>
            
            <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Award criterion price will be evaluated on the basis of "Total costs including options and estimated change orders" for implementation/Establishment cost plus the total over 8 years (contract maximum years) for "Total costs including options and estimated change orders" for "Cost/year"</cbc:Description>
          </cac:SubordinateAwardingCriterion>
          <cac:SubordinateAwardingCriterion>
            <ext:UBLExtensions>
              <ext:UBLExtension>
                <ext:ExtensionContent>
                  <efext:EformsExtension>
                    <efac:AwardCriterionParameter>
                      <efbc:ParameterCode listName="number-weight">per-exa</efbc:ParameterCode>
                      <efbc:ParameterNumeric>70</efbc:ParameterNumeric>
                    </efac:AwardCriterionParameter>
                  </efext:EformsExtension>
                </ext:ExtensionContent>
              </ext:UBLExtension>
            </ext:UBLExtensions>
            <cbc:AwardingCriterionTypeCode listName="award-criterion-type">quality</cbc:AwardingCriterionTypeCode>
            
            <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Quality</cbc:Name>
            
            <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Each SHOULD or OPTION requirement as mentioned in Step 2 clause 6.1 is awarded points on a scale from 0 to 10, where 10 is the highest score. The victim that is deemed the best for this criterion receives the highest score. The remaining offers are scored based on a discretionary assessment of how each victim compares to the best victims. If a offer lacks the necessary documentation for evaluation, the bidder will receive 0 points for the relevant award criterion.</cbc:Description>
          </cac:SubordinateAwardingCriterion>
        </cac:AwardingCriterion>
      </cac:AwardingTerms>
      <cac:AdditionalInformationParty>
        <cac:PartyIdentification>
          <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
        </cac:PartyIdentification>
      </cac:AdditionalInformationParty>
      <cac:TenderRecipientParty>
        <cbc:EndpointID>https://permalink.mercell.com/258109627.aspx</cbc:EndpointID>
        <cac:PartyIdentification>
          <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
        </cac:PartyIdentification>
      </cac:TenderRecipientParty>
      <cac:TenderEvaluationParty>
        <cac:PartyIdentification>
          <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0001</cbc:ID>
        </cac:PartyIdentification>
      </cac:TenderEvaluationParty>
      <cac:AppealTerms>
        <cac:PresentationPeriod>
          
          <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Suppliers who are rejected or whose request to participate in the competition is dismissed, as outlined in the section on supplier selection, may not file a request for an interim injunction with the district court later than 15 days after the contracting authority has sent the notification. The deadline is calculated from the day after the notification is late, in accordance with FOF § 16-5.</cbc:Description>
        </cac:PresentationPeriod>
        <cac:AppealReceiverParty>
          <cac:PartyIdentification>
            <cbc:ID schemeName="organization">ORG-0002</cbc:ID>
          </cac:PartyIdentification>
        </cac:AppealReceiverParty>
      </cac:AppealTerms>
      <cac:Language>
        <cbc:ID>NOR</cbc:ID>
      </cac:Language>
    </cac:TenderingTerms>
    <cac:TenderingProcess>
      <cbc:SubmissionMethodCode listName="esubmission">required</cbc:SubmissionMethodCode>
      <cbc:CandidateReductionConstraintIndicator>true</cbc:CandidateReductionConstraintIndicator>
      <cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:GovernmentAgreementConstraintIndicator>
      <cac:ParticipationRequestReceptionPeriod>
        <cbc:EndDate>2025-07-11+00:00</cbc:EndDate>
        <cbc:EndTime>10:00:00+00:00</cbc:EndTime>
      </cac:ParticipationRequestReceptionPeriod>
      <cac:EconomicOperatorShortList>
        <cbc:LimitationDescription>true</cbc:LimitationDescription>
        <cbc:MaximumQuantity>20</cbc:MaximumQuantity>
        <cbc:MinimumQuantity>1</cbc:MinimumQuantity>
      </cac:EconomicOperatorShortList>
      <cac:AuctionTerms>
        <cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>false</cbc:AuctionConstraintIndicator>
      </cac:AuctionTerms>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="dps-usage">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
      <cac:ContractingSystem>
        <cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode listName="framework-agreement">none</cbc:ContractingSystemTypeCode>
      </cac:ContractingSystem>
    </cac:TenderingProcess>
    <cac:ProcurementProject>
      <cbc:ID schemeName="InternalID">2025/12360</cbc:ID>
      
      <cbc:Name languageID="ENG">Step 1 - Procurement of "Software for leakage reduction and sewerage system outflow in Municipality of Trondheim" - Prequalification</cbc:Name>
      
      <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">Trondheim Municipality, hereinafter referred to as the contracting authority, invites tenders for a contract in the project ""Software for Leakage Reduction and Sewerage System Outflow in Municipality of Trondheim".</cbc:Description>
      <cbc:ProcurementTypeCode listName="contract-nature">services</cbc:ProcurementTypeCode>
      <cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
        <cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount currencyID="NOK">10000000.00</cbc:EstimatedOverallContractAmount>
      </cac:RequestedTenderTotal>
      <cac:MainCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72000000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:MainCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">48000000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">48100000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">48600000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
        <cbc:ItemClassificationCode listName="cpv">72300000</cbc:ItemClassificationCode>
      </cac:AdditionalCommodityClassification>
      <cac:RealizedLocation>
        <cac:Address>
          <cbc:CountrySubentityCode listName="nuts">NO060</cbc:CountrySubentityCode>
          <cac:Country>
            <cbc:IdentificationCode listName="country">NOR</cbc:IdentificationCode>
          </cac:Country>
        </cac:Address>
      </cac:RealizedLocation>
      <cac:PlannedPeriod>
        <cbc:DurationMeasure unitCode="MONTH">96</cbc:DurationMeasure>
      </cac:PlannedPeriod>
      <cac:ContractExtension>
        <cbc:MaximumNumberNumeric>7</cbc:MaximumNumberNumeric>
        <cac:Renewal>
          <cac:Period>
            
            <cbc:Description languageID="ENG">The Parties agree that the initial term of the Agreement shall be 1 (one) year. Thereafter, the Agreement may be extended for up to 7 (seven) additional years at the sole discretion of the Customer. Unless the Customer notifies the Supplier of its decision to terminate the Agreement in writing prior to the expiration of the initial term or any subsequent term, the Agreement shall automatically be extended for an additional term of equal duration.</cbc:Description>
          </cac:Period>
        </cac:Renewal>
      </cac:ContractExtension>
    </cac:ProcurementProject>
  </cac:ProcurementProjectLot>
</ContractNotice>